（柔和的音乐）
-[旁白]斯坦福大学。
-[讲师]我们回来了，第四节课。
斯坦福CS193p，2020年春季。
今天，我将从一个大型演示开始，
这将是制作我们的纸牌游戏
排成一排，而不是排成一排，
毫无疑问，这将使我们的游戏变得更好
但这也将是一个很好的例子
使用协议进行泛型的过程，
并用作类型。
我们将学习更多有关成为容器的信息
因为我们要建立自己的
行和列容器查看我们的卡。
演示之后，我们将跳回到此处的幻灯片。
我们将进一步讨论Swift类型的系统，
特别是类型枚举。
然后在那之后，我们将继续幻灯片
并讨论最重要的类型之一
在所有Swift中，Optional是一个枚举。
可选非常重要，我要去
之后立即返回演示
并向您展示两个非常重要的例子
在Swift中使用Optional设计代码的过程。
因此，让我们开始该演示。
好吧，这是修复此主要缺陷的类型
在我们的游戏中，这是所有的牌
在一排，
而且我们知道我们可以更有效率
如果我们有行和列，请使用此空间。
我们将通过在此处替换HStack来做到这一点
与网格。
现在，从这个班级的录音开始，
SwiftUI中没有Grid之类的东西，
所以我们要写些。
它实际上为我们提供了一个绝佳的机会
了解有关ZStack之类的工作原理的大量信息。
因此，我们知道ZStack就在这里接受此参数，
这是一个功能。
花括号表示它是一个功能。
这个函数不带参数，
与ForEach不同，它创建视图的功能
吵架
但是ZStack，这里构建的View
非常强大。
它可能是其他视图的列表。
可以是如果-则是其组合。
所以这个可以建立的特殊功能
这些复杂的View称为ViewBuilder。
而且我们还不会使用ViewBuilder。
我们最终将了解ViewBuilder。
所以我们的网格只会有一个简单的视图
它将使用ForEach复制，
与ForEach完全相同，
在每个位置放一个特定的视图
在行和列中。
因此，我们的Grid确实将像Grid一样组合HStack，
除了2D HStack，如果您想考虑一下，
像这样的ForEach。
我们将采取一系列可识别的事物，
像这些卡片，然后我们将传递一个函数
以可识别事物之一作为论据，
并返回要使用的视图
在网格中的该位置绘制。
这里很简单。
因此，让我们创建该视图。
我们将在这里转到“新建文件”。
我们将其放入自己的文件中，因为这确实
一个非常强大的可重用对象。
我们可以在需要网格的所有应用程序中使用它。
这是一个SwiftUI视图，所以我要单击此处。
我将其称为Grid。
要仔细检查它是其中之一
黄色的文件夹在这里，这个内容
有点匹配，而且确实如此，所以我们很好。
这是我们的网格，当然，我们会得到“ Hello，World！”
您会记得下面的这段代码
是为了把我们吸引到我们的画布上。
但是这个网格是完全通用的。
因此，如果我们要使该预览工作正常进行，
我们需要为此提供一些测试数据。
而且在本演示中我们不会这样做
但将来有一天，也许你可以做到
作为练习。
但是，如果您删除了它并需要它，
在画布上会在此处说“创建预览”。
好吧，所以我们必须开始使用Grid。
我们要做的第一件事是它的两个论点。
第一个参数是此可识别数组，
第二个参数是这个函数
它采用一个Identifiables并提供一个View。
因此，让我们将这两个参数作为vars获取。
因此，第一个变量是“项目”，即“项目数组”。
Grid中对我们来说这一项是无关紧要的。
我们真的不在乎那个东西是什么。
可能是任何东西。
这将是一张卡片，但是没有理由
因为它是任何特殊的东西，
所以这对我们来说不在乎。
同样，第二个论点
viewForItem我将其称为函数。
这个函数需要一个Item作为参数，
它返回一些ItemView，
这是另一个我们不在乎的。
我们真的不在乎您提供哪种视图
对于每个项目，都不必关心ItemView。
一个好的开始，我们实际上可以在这里解决。
不幸的是，我们必须在此命名该项目。
这真的是viewForItem，
放在那边
但这是此函数的最后一个参数，
所以我们知道当最后一个参数
一个功能是另一个功能，
那么我们就可以删除该标签，将其关闭，
并让我们的功能有点浮在外面。
因此，这是我们网格的最后一个参数。
这就是它的两个变量，这个变量和viewForItem。
就像我们在这里叫CardView一样
我们必须将其变量初始化为这个Card变量，
网格在这里也是一样。
我们正在初始化它的两个变量。
现在可能是谈论它的好时机
ForEach不必具有此标签项？
当我们有了ForEach时，它就有了可迭代的东西
里面有可识别的东西
怎么没有争论呢？
好吧，它使用的是您熟知的技术。
所以我们也要在Grid中做
这只是一个初始化。
所以通常你可能会有你的init说项目
是Item的数组，viewForItem是一个函数
它接受一个I​​tem并返回一些ItemView。
那将是正常的初始化。
在这里，您只想
初始化您的变量，例如项。
好吧，这等于传入的项目。
然后是viewForItem，它等于viewForItem
这已经过去了。
顺便说一句，斯威夫特在这里会很困惑
因为它不知道这是什么
以及这是什么项目。
我们对该函数有一个局部参数，称为items，
然后我们有一个称为项的属性。
这样您就可以在这里轻松解决Swift的困惑
通过说出self.items和self.viewForItem。
这是不得不将自己放在这里的另一个原因
比我们看到的明确的自我blah-blah命中修复方法要好。
但这在这里有意义，对吗？
通过执行self.items，现在Swift知道我们在说
关于绿色的，
而且这个一定是黑色的。
现在，这使我们可以将这个限制
作为外部名称。
记住下标是外部名称
表示不提供外部名称，
而这正是这里发生的事情。
如果我重建，你会看到
这段代码在这里，非常好。
但是，我们的网格仍然存在问题。
这个错误就在这里。
它说：“分配非转义参数
“将'viewForItem'转换为@转义的闭包。”
所以我将尝试解释这种逃逸的关闭
在短短几分钟内。
通常，我实际上可能会有幻灯片。
我本季将跳过该季度，因为在SwiftUI中，
由于我们正在执行函数式编程，
几乎所有东西都是价值类型
以及这个逃逸的东西关闭的问题
试图在这里解决
在SwiftUI中确实非常罕见。
当我们进行面向对象编程时，发生了很多事情
在UIkit中。
所以，这就是发生的事情。
这里传递的这个功能
为给定项目创建视图
在此初始值设定项中未实际使用。
我们将其盐腌入var中，稍后再调用。
我们要在我们体内称呼它
当我们需要实际创建视图时
对于我们所有的物品。
因此，我们必须标记这种功能@escaping。
您可以将其视为此功能
将从这个初始化程序中逃脱
没有被叫。
现在，Swift必须要小心，
它实际上非常强大
并且知道如何处理这些功能
以后可能会打电话给您。
为什么会是一个问题？
好吧，让我们回顾这里
传递此功能。
无论此处包含什么代码，都必须稍后才能调用。
因此，如果我们使用任何变量，尤其是如果我们使用
局部变量或此函数中的某些内容，
将来必须存在
该函数执行时。
现在，斯威夫特如何完成这项奇妙的壮举
把所有东西都留在这里直到将来？
好吧，它是通过创建函数类型来实现的
是参考类型。
就像类一样，我们的ViewModel是引用类型，
他们住在堆里。
它们存储在内存中。
人们有指向他们的指针。
这些功能相同，可以稍后调用。
它们生活在堆中，并且有指向它们的指针。
现在，这里的东西也可能存在于堆中。
例如，如果这里的任何东西都是类，
那么这里的自我将成为一个指针
堆中的东西。
而我们试图在Swift中避免的问题
在自我中有一些变种
实际指向此功能
因为我们知道这个功能在这里指向自我。
他们俩都会在堆里。
该函数保存在堆中
因为它将稍后执行。
函数内部的所有内容都保留在堆中
以便以后可以正确执行。
因此，如果这里有任何提示，
我们遇到了堆中有两件事的情况
互相指向。
以及Swift清理内存的方式
当没有人指出某事时
它清理内存并释放它
供其他人使用。
好吧，如果两件事互相指向
他们都在堆里，
他们永远也不会消失
因为它们总是相互之间有一个指针。
这就是所谓的记忆周期。
所以，这整个过程就是要努力做到
这样我们就可以检测到记忆周期
通过查看这些转义功能。
令人惊讶的是，这也是为什么您会收到关于自我的警告。
你知道我们什么时候不放点
在我们的onTapGesture函数中
我们将得到这个错误，说
这需要明确的自我
使捕获语义明确。
捕获语义意味着事实
捕捉这里的一切，
在此onTapGesture函数中，
并将其保留在堆中，以便在onTapGesture
将来在有人点击此即时贴时执行
这些东西仍然存在。
好吧，如果您看这段代码，
您在想，“哦，我想它捕获了ViewModel，”
但实际上它必须捕获自己。
所以它让你输入自我
让你意识到，哦，是的，
这个功能将使自己成为记忆。
然后您可以验证自己实际上并没有
以某种方式直接或间接地回来
并指向此功能，
在这种情况下它不会执行此操作，因为在这里，
我们的ViewModel从不指向我们的视图。
视图指向ViewModel，但不指向反向，
所以没问题
但更重要的是，因为这个自我点
反正不存在于堆中。
这个自我点就是这个结构，自我就是这个结构。
结构是值类型。
他们不住在堆里。
因此，无论如何都没有必要。
这就是已经公开批准的解决方案，
你可能会看到几个月
制作完这段视频之后。
所以这部影片很快就会过时了。
但解决方法基本上是自我，在这种情况下，
这些转义功能之一的内部
会被堆在堆里
如果自我不生活在堆里，
换句话说，它是一个值类型，一个结构或一个枚举，
那么您不需要出现此错误
并警告您：“嘿，在上面加点
“因此，请确保您没有记忆周期
“自我指向此功能的地方，
“这个功能指向自我。”
那不可能发生，因为没有两件事
在可能指向对方的堆中
因为自我是一种结构。
这是一个值类型，不存在于堆中。
因此，您只需要快速了解一下
所有这些转义，你甚至现在都明白
这个自我点是什么。
如果你听不懂我说的话
关于这些转义功能和这个自圆点，
真的，我认为您不必为此担心
有几个原因。
一，这周的读物，你会读
关于这些闭包，这些功能
在线捕捉他们需要的东西
以便以后执行。
因此，当您阅读该书时，也许您会理解的。
当然，您始终可以选择
进入课堂论坛，询问更多有关澄清的信息。
最后，使用SwiftUI并不是那么重要
因为这么多的自我点只是值类型。
例如，视图中的所有内容都是值类型。
我们的ViewModel，是一个类。
它有可能。
但是由于ViewModel从不指向任何东西
在视图中，我们永远不必担心
关于视图中创建这些内存周期的任何内容。
这将是非常罕见的。
可以做，但是非常非常罕见。
所以最重要的是，我认为您不必担心
这么多。
唯一会困扰你的事情
是你总是要把自我点
在这些事情面前，
否则您将不得不处理此错误
并执行此操作，单击它，然后一直进行修复。
同样，这只是您要做的事情
直到这个公开事物的beta发布，
并希望在几个月内。
但是，最坏的情况是几个月。
在那之后，您将不必为此担心
完全是因为不把自己放在这里
当self是一个值类型时，不会生成此警告。
那就是建议的解决方法。
好吧，仅此而已。
这一切都是因为我们收到了这个警告
告诉我们我们必须在这里逃跑
因为确实，此函数确实会从此init逃脱
因为我们把它放在这个变量中。
让我们做自己的身体。
我们的身体不是“你好，世界！”明显。
我们的身体实际上很简单。
这只是我们所有产品的前身。
对于我们的每个项目，我们将返回
该Item的viewForItem。
我们将调用我们的函数viewForItem。
这是一个变量，这就是我们要称之为的函数。
当然，我们想要ForEach。
它还具有用于视图的转义功能，
所以我们必须说点自我。
这给我们带来了一些错误，让我们来看一下。
第一个说：“无法转换类型的值
“预期参数类型为“ Range of Int”的项目数组。”
哦，不，我们看到了这个确切的论点问题
当我们第一次在这里做ForEach时。
我们正在通过这一系列卡片
而且我们就像，哦，我以为我可以做到。
我们过去传递的零点数少于
我们去了Array，我告诉过你
此ForEach采用一个数组。
但是我们了解到这是一个数组
只有可识别的事物。
所以我们在这里有同样的问题。
该项目的这个ForEach必须是一个数组
可识别的事物。
嗯，这对我们来说是个问题，因为Item是无关紧要的。
我们不知道这是什么东西。
但是，这是我们在行为中获得约束和收获的地方。
我们要说项目在哪里可识别。
所以现在我们创建了一个仅适用于
当您不在乎时，可以忽略此内容。
因此，这仍然可以是任何东西。
但是它必须是可识别的。
这就是我在幻灯片中所说的，
有点关心的事情。
我们有点关心Item。
我们关心它是可识别的。
所以现在我们这里有一个不同的错误。
这个ForEach错误是说
“归还财产'身体'的类型”，这就是我们的身体，
“要求'ItemView'符合'View'。”
那么什么是ItemView？
这是此函数的返回类型。
当然，这很有意义
因为ForEach只能使用视图来拥有视图
这些物品。
这必须是一个视图。
因此，这里的ViewForItem返回类型是ItemView，
它必须是一个视图。
那是什么类型？
这也不在乎。
我们将在这里做同样的事情。
ItemView必须是一个View。
大家都看到了我们如何连接泛型，
这是带有协议的非常通用的结构。
这些是协议，我们正在使用它们来约束
这些无关紧要的工作。
我们在这里要做的下一件事是我们是一个容器。
网格包含所有这些视图。
它将它们放在行和列中。
它包含它们。
而且我们知道容器的工作就是占用空间
提供给他们并划分
里面的东西。
这意味着我们需要找出多少空间
已分配给我们。
我们知道该怎么做。
那就是GeometryReader。
好的，GeometryReader。
几何形状将允许我们
找出给网格多少空间，
然后我们将要交给这些家伙。
所以，把它放在这里。
现在，一旦放在这里，
当然，我们会遇到物品的自残问题。
我将使用与上次相同的解决方案，
我要在这里创建一个名为
主体（尺寸：CGSize）。
当然会返回一些视图。
我要把我的代码放在这里。
在这里，我要做一个self.body（for：geometry.size）。
再说一次，这纯粹是为了做到这一点
因此我不必在此体内做自我标记。
就像GeometryReader逃逸一样
所以我们做了这个self.body，
ForEach也正在逃避，
所以我要在这里做同样的事情
self.body（用于商品，大小）。
我要搬到
另一个小功能主体（用于物品，尺寸）
打开一些视图。
现在，我不需要在这里加点。
只需退还。
因此，我们在这里很好地安排了代码。
我们剩下要做的，信不信由你，
实际上是在我们的某些空间中提供这些视图，
然后定位它们。
这就是容器的作用。
提供空间，他们就位。
为此，我们需要做一些数学运算
因为我们得到了这个空间，
现在我们需要将其除以许多项
我们在这里。
为了做那个数学，我实际上写了一些代码
我给你的，我们将在这里使用。
让我们将其拖入。
顺便说一下，当您拖入代码时，
如果需要，请务必执行此操作。
几乎总是您想要的。
您希望将该代码的副本放入您的项目中。
否则，它将指向您的桌面
或从何处拖动它。
好的，我们完成了。
因此，在这里让我们看一下这一点。
这是数学，这是GridLayout。
数学，它会进行此计算，
让我们来看一下。
现在，我在这里折叠了init和这两个var和func
因为我们不会看这些的实现。
在这堂课之后，我确实鼓励你，
去看看实现，
看看是否可以解决。
您需要本讲义的其余部分来掌握相关知识
才能真正了解它在做什么，
但是尝试并理解这是一个很好的练习。
大约只有10行代码，
因此您应该不会有太多麻烦。
但是，这是GridLayout的作用。
其初始值设定项包含许多项目和一个大小，
然后将其除以这些项目。
它完全符合Grid的要求。
现在，它甚至还允许您指定所需的宽高比。
它不能保证，但是可以尝试接近它。
就是这样，我们只需创建一个做到这一点的GridLayout。
然后我们在这里有一个变量，它将告诉我们大小
大小相同的商品中，
所以这就是大小。
然后还将每个项目的位置作为一个点。
这是每个项目的中心，
同样，这正是Grid想要的。
所以GridLayout绝对是考虑到Grid的，
但这几乎是CGSize的通用划分
一定数量的项目。
因此，让我们创建此GridLayout
通过在此处调用此初始化程序。
我要在我的GeometryReader中完成它。
实际上，我将更改此尺寸的传递
而是传递GridLayout。
而itemCount只是Items的数量
我们有。
这是我们的项目Array，在这里，其数量。
我将跳过所需的宽高比的东西。
我们将使用任何默认值。
希望您在阅读中看到可以
函数的默认参数，并且GridLayout使用它。
但是你一定要有尺寸
这当然是在geometry.size中。
而且我们仍然在这里的GeometryReader
所以这个项目必须是self.items。
这是一个实例变量。
因此，我更改了此正文。
现在不再是尺寸的主体，而是布局的主体。
GridLayout在这里。
同样，我将不得不通过
所以现在是body（for：项目，in：布局）。
所以这也使它成为布局，
沿线向下传递。
现在我们在这里，我们有了这个布局，
并且我们已经按照尺寸大小列出了商品的数量。
因此，我们可以轻松地进行诸如为这些视图提供空间，
我们用框架来做。
所以我们要说框架的宽度
是布局的itemSize.width，
框架的高度为layout.itemSize.height。
我们将提供相同的小空间
每个物品的空间。
这就是GridLayout中的itemSize。
再次，GridLayout创建了这么多项目
在提供给我们的尺寸上。
这就是我们将其划分的方式。
然后我们必须定位视图
所以我们按位置来做。
这就是我们要做的功能。
我们将其放置在版面的位置
ofItemAt索引。
因此，这已被索引，就像我们使用卡片时一样。
所以我们必须找到该项目的索引
在我们的商品数组中。
没问题，我们有点知道该怎么做。
我们说让索引相等，
嗯，我知道该怎么做。
我要在此商品的自我索引上创建一个函数。
我要去这里说（项的）func索引。
并且它将返回一个Int，即数组的索引。
我们先在这里返回零，
然后我们马上填写。
现在，这将再次让Swift感到困惑
因为您有索引，此局部变量，
然后索引此函数。
因此，我们可以用相同的方法再次修复该问题。
现在知道该索引是函数，
这个索引是我们正在创建的局部变量。
因此，我们实际上使用了自我点。
即使他们使用值类型进行更改
自我标记不会像这样被标记
我们有时还是想使用自点
定义属性之间的区别
或函数与局部变量
或函数的参数。
好吧，在这里的索引中，我们如何找到该项目
在数组中？
好吧，你猜怎么着？
这些项目是可识别的。
也许你们当中有些像
“嗯，这似乎太熟悉了。”
是的，我们要做索引
以零点表示的点数小于items.count
我们有。
如果该[index] .id中的项目
等于该商品的ID，
然后我们将返回该索引。
否则我们将返回零，
这与我们上次这样做一样虚假。
现在，此功能有点双重伪造。
这是虚假的，因为我们仍在执行此返回零。
换句话说，如果我们找不到项目
在我们的商品中，我们将只退回第一件商品，
索引为零。
真是假
但是，还有一个错误是，这段代码是完全一样的，
是的，因为此代码在我们的模型中。
所以，伙计，你永远不想写
完全一样的代码，像这样两次。
那只是糟糕的编程。
好吧，我们将在一分钟内解决该问题。
但是首先让我们看看我们的网格是否有效。
信不信由你，这就是我们网格所需要的。
没有别的了。
因此，我们得到了提供给我们的空间。
我们使用此GridLayout对其进行划分，
然后我们将其提供给其中的小子视图，
然后我们将它们放置在那些位置
在GridLayout中。
这就是所需要的，所以让我们在这里进行一下测试。
看看是否有效。
嗯，确实如此。
瞧瞧，我们的六张卡已不再连续。
让我们去风景，看看，它调整了卡片的大小
以更好地适应空间。
现在，我想要一点填充
卡之间，但这是回事
当我们创建CardView时
我们可以在上面放一些填充物。
如果我们在这些CardView周围放置一些填充
在网格内部，嗯，我们得到了填充。
很好。
也许我们不需要太多填充。
也许我们只想填充五个。
运行它。
呵呵，看起来不错。
好的，既然我们的网格正在工作，
让我们去修复我们这里存在的虚假代码，
这是项目的索引。
这是假的，因为这完全重复了
这另一件事。
让我们考虑一下这里发生的事情。
在这两种情况下，我们实际上是在要求什么？
我们有一系列可识别的事物，
希望我们有其中之一。
我们知道它也是可识别的。
我们想看看是否可以找到它。
因此，听起来更像是Array。
让我们向Array添加一个执行此操作的函数。
扩展数组。
但仅限于数组中的元素
是可识别的。
因此，它又再次成为制约和收获。
此扩展仅将添加此功能
我们想要添加到此类数组中的内容。
因此，它是相同的功能。
实际上，我只是要复制并粘贴
我们将对其进行修改，甚至剪切并粘贴。
切掉那边。
将此粘贴在这里。
这里不一样
因为我们在这里看物品。
显然，这是一个数组函数，
所以现在物品是自我。
还有同样的事情。
这不是物品的计数。
这是自我的计数。
这个项目的类型，项目的索引，不是项目。
这是元素，因为这就是我们要寻找的
在一个数组。
我们有一个数组，其元素都是可识别的
我们在这里说的是获取索引
可识别的此数组的元素之一
通过查找。
现在，这是正确的，这做对了，
但实际上我不喜欢在这里选择的命名。
关于这一点的一件事是它实际上并没有返回
该项目的索引。
它返回找到的第一个。
从零开始遍历数组，
当找到一个时，将其返回。
因此，这确实是此项的第一个索引。
我也不喜欢这个词。
项目在网格中有意义
因为我们有物品。
“项目”一词遍地都是。
但实际上在Array中，Item不是一回事。
有元素，但没有项目。
实际上，这是第一个索引
匹配该元素。
所以我将使用firstIndex匹配作为我的名字。
感觉更像是Array函数，
firstIndex与此元素匹配。
那么，我们如何在这里使用它呢？
而不是self.index，
我们只是要说项目，数组，
点firstIndex匹配项。
因此，我们要求Array立即执行此操作，
去找到与该项目匹配的第一个索引。
我们可以在这里做完全相同的事情。
我们甚至不再需要此功能。
我们在这里得到它是因为我们知道我们的卡阵列
在这里可以做与Card匹配的firstIndex。
因此，我们正在重用此代码。
看看我们的模型有多小。
它很小，这里几乎没有任何代码。
其中一些是因为我们刚刚制作了Array
查找此功能的功能更强大。
与网格相同。
网格的代码很少
因为我们利用了这个数组。
现在，这与Grid无关。
因此它不属于Grid.swift。
因此，我将其剪切为Grid.swift。
我将其放入自己的文件中。
它不是SwiftUI视图。
这只是一个普通的Swift文件。
现在，当我们进行这样的扩展时，
我们通常将文件扩展名为Array，我们正在扩展的东西，
加上某种描述符
是什么样的东西
因此，这是可识别的
数组+可识别。
因此，让我们进入这里。
在那里。
粘贴进去。
请注意，这是导入基金会，
很好。
这不是UI问题。
这纯粹是数组和可标识的。
这些都不是UI的东西。
所以我们回到网格。
在这里进行构建，以便它注意到所有这些东西。
并确保我们的模型也可以正常工作。
没有错误，实际上，我们整个程序都没有错误。
让我们运行，确保数组确实正在执行。
好吧，再一次，我们正在使用整个概念
的约束和收获。
在这里，我们限制了数组的无关类型
这样就可以识别它们
这样我们就可以使用此功能。
对于所有标识了元素的数组，它们都会得到此结果。
没有没有可识别元素的数组，
他们甚至看不到此功能。
甚至在Xcode中也无法完全逃脱。
甚至不在那里。
而且我们正在做同样的事情
在这里有限制和收获
使其成为我们的网格始终是网格
可识别的事物，将两个事物匹配为视图。
本演示就是这样。
所以我要回到幻灯片，
我们将解决此问题。
我们需要Swift中称为Optional的类型，
一个非常非常重要的类型，它是一个枚举。
因此，让我们快速回顾一下枚举是什么，
然后我们将讨论
这个非常重要的类型，可选。
枚举只是另一种类型，例如struct或class，
但是对于枚举，该值是离散的。
这里的好例子，FastFoodMenuItem是一个汉堡包
还是薯条，饮料或饼干。
别无其他。
要成为这四件事之一。
那是菜单上唯一的东西，
它必须是其中之一，并且只是其中之一。
像结构一样，枚举是一种值类型。
传递时被复制。
它不存在于堆中。
没有指向它的指针。
这是一个值类型。
现在，Swift中的枚举最酷的地方是
与大多数其他语言不同，
是每个离散值
可以有一些相关的数据
这是特定于特定离散值的。
例如，我们这里有汉堡包。
如果FastFoodMenuItem是一个汉堡包，
我们要说多少馅饼？
这是两倍还是三倍还是单倍？
如果是薯条，这是大薯条还是小薯条？
如果是饮料，您会在那看到，您有饮料，
是可乐，胡椒博士等等。
请注意，这里没有为String命名，
所以这些东西不必一定要有名字。
您在这里看到的这种黄色语法
从阅读中可能看起来很熟悉。
这只是一个元组。
因此，所有元组规则都允许您使用标签
或没有标签，并在这里有您想要的数量，
全部完全有效
作为此处的关联数据值。
那么如何设置枚举的值呢？
非常简单
你只说枚举的名字，
如FastFoodMenuItem，点，离散值，
汉堡或饼干，例如这里。
现在，当然，如果有关联的数据，
您必须提供相关数据。
在这种情况下，汉堡（馅饼：2）。
它无法制造汉堡包
如果不知道有多少馅饼
现在Swift可以在这里进行类型推断
这样您就不必键入FastFoodMenuItem
双方平等。
但是您必须小心一点。
你必须把它放在平等的一面
因为如果你只是说
var yetAnotherItem等于Cookie，
Swift没有足够的信息
推断我们在这里谈论快餐菜单项。
可能是任何有cookie的东西。
所以你必须在某个地方出现FastFoodMenuItem
以便Swift可以推断。
我们如何检查值？
您可能会认为这就像一个假设。
你知道，如果这个菜单项等于一个汉堡，
然后做点什么。
但是我们不使用if枚举。
我们使用此表达式开关。
现在，开关以其他语言存在。
它在Swift中非常强大
不仅用于检查您将要看到的枚举，
但是它有正则表达式匹配
和各种各样的东西。
再一次，你希望读到
在阅读作业中。
因此，如果我想检查menuItem的值，
我要打开menuItem，
然后有一个案例陈述
对于每个可能的menuItem。
它必须是每一个。
现在，我不在这里
关联的数据，在这里我可以忽略它。
我仍然可以使用Case FastFoodMenuItem.hamburger
打印单词burger。
我不能说是多少馅饼
因为我没有看相关的数据。
我要告诉你一秒钟。
但是我仍然可以在这里打印汉堡。
斯威夫特当然可以推断
这些都是快餐菜单项，
所以你不必说
每次都是FastFoodMenuItem.hamburger。
您可以仅打开menuItem。
使用.hamburger，.fries和.drink。
在这种情况下，它知道menuItem是FastFoodMenuItem。
顺便说一句，开关要求您遮盖
每一个可能的情况。
因此，您可能会有一个案例，例如汉堡包，
你不在乎的
您不想打印出汉堡包。
在这种情况下，您可以说休息一下。
因此，突破突围，
并说案子.hamburger中断意味着它将无能为力
如果菜单项是汉堡包。
同样，如果您真的只关心几种情况
其他所有，您都可以执行一些默认行为，
您可以使用特殊关键字default。
因此，如果您未列出，则会发生默认情况
一个特定的情况。
但是您必须做另一件事。
要么你有所有的情况
而那些你不在乎的人会爆发出来，
或者你只能有一些情况，
但是您必须提供此默认情况。
通常在交换机中是必需的。
不只是枚举，而且在Swift中，
开关需要完全覆盖
所有的可能性。
那相关的数据呢？
好吧，我们也可以在切换中做到这一点。
我们只在这里以黄色添加您看到的内容
当我们说案例。汉堡时，
我们说括号，让pattyCount。
这将获取与汉堡相关的数据
并将其分配给这个很小的局部变量pattyCount
仅对此打印语句有效
或这个汉堡之后发生的一切。
炸薯条也是一样。
例如，这种饮料很有趣。
因此，饮料将抢占品牌和盎司。
请注意，盎司在我声明时曾经带有标签，
但是我没有在那做，没关系
因为这是元组。
元组，如果要在两面都可以使用标签，
声明和使用它。
因此，这是完全相同的事情
您可以在其中获取相关值
但是，您想抓住它。
好吧，让我们看看。
方法，是的，您可以在枚举上使用方法。
无论您想做什么，它几乎都是无限的。
属性，您可以计算出属性，
但是您不能有任何存储的属性。
带有枚举的所有存储
仅在这些关联的值中，
有点意思，因为一个枚举是一个离散的事情。
拥有其他数据真的没有任何意义
适用于所有这些。
那不是离散的。
因此，这就是为什么您必须这样做。
开启自我。
好吧，如果您的枚举中包含函数，
它实际上应该告诉你一些东西
关于枚举，这是很常见的
具有这些功能。
这里我有这个函数isIncludedInSpecialOrder号，
会说这个FastFoodMenuItem
包含在特定的特殊顺序中。
为此，我必须打开自己
看看我是什么，看看我是否被包括在内
以这种特殊的顺序。
这样您就可以看到我有很多示例。
我想更仔细地研究这些例子之一，
这是这个饮料的例子。
请注意，它正在开关中获取关联的值
盎司，但它忽略了
无论是可乐还是胡椒博士。
我们不在乎。
是否包含在内都没有关系
以特殊的顺序。
因此，此下标是无需关注的地方，
本质上我不感兴趣。
就像我们有功能一样
它具有带有外部名称的参数
和内部名称，我们使用下划线表示
我们对外部名称不感兴趣，请勿使用它。
这也是这里的意思。
所以这就是如果您有一些相关的价值
作为具有多个要素的元组，
您可以忽略其中一些
当您获得价值时。
枚举可以通过协议来约束和收获
就像结构和类一样。
有一个非常有趣的协议，称为CaseIterable。
CaseIterable，您将获得一个名为allCases的变量。
它是静态var，因此您将其发送给类型，
就像这里，在这里看到的TeslaModel.allCases。
这只会给您带来麻烦
在所有情况下，您都可以做一些事情。
那可能是非常有价值的。
在作业三中，您可能要去
需要使用它。
现在我们知道了一个枚举，
我们可以谈论最重要的枚举
在所有Swift中，这称为Optional。
因此，一个Optional基本上看起来像这样。
它有两个离散值。
一种情况是没有情况，一种情况是一些情况。
在某些情况下，它具有关联的价值，
不在乎。
因此，可选，可选适用于任何类型。
不管它是什么类型。
因此从本质上讲，Optional是
是一个固定的情况，就是这样，
或没有设置的情况，就是没有。
这就是可选的。
本质上是一种类型。
您将拥有Optional类型的变量。
他们将被设置或未设置。
如果设置了它们，它们将具有关联的价值
某种类型，而Optional不在乎是什么类型。
那么我们在哪里使用Optional？
好吧，您可以想象我们会随时使用它
我们有一个变量，其值
可能未设置，未指定或不确定，
诸如此类的东西。
有什么例子？
好吧，该假返回的firstIndex匹配类型。
如果匹配的东西不在数组中，
我们目前返回零。
那是数组中的第一个元素。
那是完全错误的。
因此，我们将拥有firstIndex匹配的
返回类型为Optional。
这将是一个Optional，而相关的值为Int。
因此，它要么返回设置，要么不设置。
如果能够的话，它将返回设置
关联的值将是索引。
否则它将返回未设置状态
如果它在那里找不到匹配的东西。
普通变量的另一个很好的例子
假设是在模型的配对游戏中
如果我有一个像这样的变量怎么办
当前面朝上卡的索引？
好的，当游戏开始时，没有面朝上的卡片。
那么那个索引是什么呢？
就像，它没有设置。
因此，我们将使用Optional来存储它。
该var不会是索引的Int类型。
它的类型将为Optional。
现在关联的值将是一个Int
当然，如果已设置，
我们想知道Int是什么。
我要展示几个很好的例子
在此之后的演示中。
因此，这种情况经常发生
您需要一些有时未设置的变量，
未指定。
您想返回一个值，说我做不到，
这样的东西。
因此，Swift引入了很多语法糖，
基本上是特殊的语法，以便使其变得真正容易
使用Optional，以至于您会认为
在Swift中，Optionals只是一种魔术类型。
但是，所有这一切都只是这个枚举。
确实没有什么比这更多的了。
因此，让我们看一下所有这些语法糖。
第一个是我们如何声明或说
我们想要这种类型？
所以在这里以黄色显示，您看到的是String ？。
那就是说你好，这个var你好，
是Optional类型的
一个可选的，其关联值为字符串。
我们将其称为Optional String。
当学生第一次接触到这一点时，
他们认为hello的类型是String
以某种方式修改为可选。
不，您好的类型是可选的。
它的关联值是一个字符串，但它是可选的。
这就是我们声明的方式。
这就是我们键入类型的方式，
我们如何用手指键入“可选字符串”类型。
现在如何设置值？
很好记住，一个可选的字符串，它是一个可选的。
它只有两种情况，没有和一些。
因此，我们只说等于nil就设置了none。
因此，Swift中的关键字nil表示Optional.none。
这意味着未设置Optional的情况为nil。
同样，我们可以说，你好，
此Optional String等于String hello。
斯威夫特足够聪明，知道那意味着
将此情况设置为Optional
并使用hello作为关联值。
这样就设置了String（在这种情况下，您好），
并且它的关联值是hello。
请注意，Optionals总是开始
隐式等于nil。
很好，因为请记住在结构和类中，
所有变量必须具有初始值。
我们跳了很多圈
尝试获取我们所有的var
到目前为止具有初始值。
好吧，可选，没有任何障碍
因为它得到一个隐式等于nil，
或在枚举世界中，对于所有var来说，都为无。
没错，对，因为这里有一个Optional。
它已设置或未设置。
好吧，它将开始没有设置。
如果您愿意，可以将其初始化为“ hello”，
但是您可以不对其进行初始化，
但是它并不是真正未初始化的。
确实将其初始化为none。
那么如何访问值呢？
假设我有一个像你好一样的变种，
这是一个Optional，Optional String，
我想要的字符串。
如何获得字符串？
我如何获得相关的价值？
我要做什么，就像您在右边看到的那样，
打开它，然后做这种情况？
当然不是。
有一种简单的方法可以打开它。
实际上有两种方式。
一是感叹号。
如果您在变数后面加上感叹号
这是一个可选的，它将假设
在某些情况下，固定的情况下，
并获得相关的价值。
但是，如果不是这样，它将导致程序崩溃。
感叹号是真的，我们称之为
强制展开，因为您要强制展开
被解开，给我那个字符串。
但是如果那个字符串不存在
因为在未设置的情况下是Optional，
然后它会使您的程序崩溃。
我们将在演示中看到
这听起来像啊，我永远都不会使用。
我永远不会希望我的程序崩溃。
但这实际上可能非常有用
如果您知道这是绝对不应该的
确实如此。
您可以轻松找到开发中的错误以及所有这些
通过使事情崩溃并说，
“哇，那本不应该崩溃的。”
但是有一种安全的方法
就是将其分配给另一个变量，
一个安全的变量。
如果允许，您可以这样做。
所以你在这里的左下角看到
如果让路，所有黄色都围绕着。
你说，如果允许的话，一些安全的版本，
等于Optional，hello是Optional，
那么那个safehello将是String类型的。
如果可选，它将获得值
在某些情况下。
然后在里面的花括号里面，
如果让safehello等于打开花括号，
在那个大括号中，safehello将存在于其中，
这将是一个字符串。
不是可选的。
它安全地从Optional中获取了相关的值
并正在执行。
现在，如果在未设置的情况下打个招呼，
那么它甚至不会执行该代码
那说print（safehello）。
甚至不会被执行。
它会做一些其他的事情。
就像在右下角，
打个招呼。
如果是在未设置的情况下，
你会做那别的。
否则，在某些情况下，
那么你将要把字符串放到那边
并在那里进行打印（safehello）。
这就是我们获取价值的方法，语法糖
用于获取Optional的值。
要么强行从那里抓起
如果我们找不到它就会崩溃
或做一个安全变量
一个安全的着陆点。
另一个很酷的小语法糖
是Optional默认值。
因此，这可以让您真正简单地提供一个默认
当您访问可选项时
如果在未设置的情况下是Optional，
所以等于零
这里我有一个叫做x的常数
类型为“可选字符串”，“可选字符串”。
我可能已经将其设置为某些内容。
也许我将其设置为nil，也许我将其设置为某些东西。
但是现在我要说的是y等于x。
但是，如果x为零，请使用foo。
那就是那个问号-问号
就是在那里
因此，在这种情况下，y始终为String类型。
因为如果x是可选情况，则在设定的情况下
并且它具有关联的值，y会得到它。
但是如果x在未设置的情况下，
然后这个问号-问号会让你
获得foo的值。
好吧，所以显示在右边
那里的枚举形式会是什么样子。
好的，因此最好在实践中了解可选方案，
所以我们要做两件事
在此演示中带有Optionals。
一个，我们要修复匹配的firstIndex
如我所说。
第二，我们要创造自己的游戏，
实际玩记忆游戏，开始匹配卡片。
而要做到这一点，
要有一个跟踪的变量
这张卡面朝上。
因为当卡片正面朝上时，
当有人拿起另一张卡时，我必须匹配它。
因此，让我们深入研究该演示。
好吧，既然我们知道什么是可选的，
我们可以用它来修复这个假的东西
我们就在这里。
这是什么假的？
好吧，我们有这个功能找到了第一个索引
与可识别数组中的某些元素匹配。
它做到了。
它通过并找到了第一个。
但是，如果找不到它，它将返回零。
零表示数组中第一件事的索引，
如果此Array为空，则尤其假，
可能是这样。
那么我们该如何解决呢？
我们将通过返回类型来解决此问题，
而不是Int，它将是可选的。
注意，我说这个表达式是可选的。
这是一个Optional，其关联值为Int，
但这是可选的。
人们一开始有时会感到困惑
认为这是一个Int
加上一些修饰符。
不，这是与Int不同的类型。
这是一个名为Optional的类型。
我们可以将其称为Optional Int，
让我们在这里返回零，
或在找不到时设置未设置的可选值。
而且非常擅长与任何人交流
谁叫这个，“我找不到这个。”
我们正常的回报是返回一个Int，
Swift当然很聪明
如果您有一个可选的Int并返回一个Int，
它将在设置状态下返回Optional
关联值为Int，
正是您想要的。
就是这样。
现在，无论如何它不再是虚假的功能，
这是一个非常好的功能。
我们可以在我们称之为的两个地方使用它。
让我们转到网格。
让我们从这个开始。
所以这是使用firstIndex的Grid。
正在获取索引。
这个局部变量就在这里，
如果我们现在选择单击它，
现在为Optional Int类型。
好吧，这将是一个问题
我们会看到一个错误出现在这里，
这是“必须解开可选类型Int的值
“达到Int的值。”
实际上，ItemAt的layout.location
不以Optional作为其参数。
它需要一个Int。
现在我们可以接受这件事的建议
说好吧，让我们打开它。
这就是我们解开Optional的方式。
这需要一个处于设置状态的Optional，
并获取其关联值。
但是，当Optional处于未设置状态时，
这会使您的程序崩溃。
现在有些人可能会说
“哇，我们为什么要使用感叹号？
“这太可怕了，有时会使我的程序崩溃。”
是的，但是在这种情况下，可能实际上是很好的
离开这里的感叹号。
因为永远不会这样
我们查找其中一项的第一个索引，
我们只能通过项目数组通过ForEaching获得。
这绝对不能为零。
如果没有，那就出了什么问题了
我的代码中的某个地方，我有点希望它崩溃
所以我发现了这个问题。
但是也许我真的很保守
当我将代码发送给客户时，
我真的想确保，无论如何
它不会因为这些惊叹号之一而崩溃。
因此，我可以保护客户
通过保护此代码，并说是否索引
不等于nil，则执行此操作。
这将保护此代码
这样它就不会崩溃。
因为如果index不为nil，则在此处展开​​它
总是会上班。
但这没有建立。
为什么不构建此代码？
它说：“缺少函数返回
“预期会返回“某些视图”。”
确实，该函数应该返回“某些视图”。
在索引的情况下，它确实会返回“ some View”
不是nil，但是如果index为nil，
当前，它什么也不返回。
那是个问题。
我什至不确定我们要返回什么
在这种情况下。
所以，我们将不得不采取一些不同的策略
返回具有条件的“某些视图”。
而且我们之前已经看过。
在我们的视图ZStack中。
ZStack有条件。
如果该卡面朝上，它会做一件事。
如果是面朝下的，那就做另一件事。
ZStack在这里使用的这个功能，请记住，
被称为ViewBiulder。
这是我们的GeometryReader所做的事情，
ForEach需要做的同样的事情，HStack，
他们都使用ViewBuilder这个功能，
但这是一种特殊的功能
您可以在其中放置这些if-thens
您可以只列出视图。
一切都变成了某种东西
那就是“某些视图”。
因此，ZStack可以将“某些视图”作为其内容。
好吧，我们可以在Grid上做同样的事情，
但我们不需要进行任何布局。
我们正在使用我们的框架和位置进行布局。
所以我们想要一些需要ViewBuilder的东西
那有点什么都不做。
而且有这样的事情。
它称为组。
因此，Group就像ZStack或其他任何事物
它的功能参数是一个“视图”构建器。
但是，它对这里的内容没有任何作用。
它允许您执行if if thens以及所有这些操作，
您仍然可以列出这些东西，
但这并没有把它们摆出来
或尝试以任何方式定位它们。
因此，我们的定位将继续在这里进行。
因此，我们将其转换为两行函数
而不是一个班轮，所以我们必须在这里放回程
以确保我们返回小组。
但是现在我们要返回Group，这是一些视图。
而Group只是使用View builder的东西
像这样去
现在，您可能会问：“如果索引为零，Group会做什么？”
好吧，那会回来的
有某种空白的内容。
它的身体将是一个空洞的视图。
实际上有一个名为EmptyView的视图。
可能会返回，但我们真的不在乎。
我们只是在这里使用ViewBuilder功能
当我们知道我们可以做的时候。
我们会发现该组很有用
在许多其他情况下也是如此。
顾名思义，它对分组非常有用。
这是因为集团，其观点在这里
是一个ViewBuilder视图。
这就是为什么我们能够做到的
但这也是为什么我们能够列出一些视图的原因，
然后将它们分组。
因此，这实际上可能是Group存在的主要原因。
这就是为什么将其称为“组”。
但是说实话，我真的可能没有
经历了所有麻烦。
我认为没有任何原因
检查该索引是否为零。
正如我之前提到的，它永远不应为零。
因此，我可能会删除所有这些内容。
回到我们以前的地方。
并让该索引强制展开。
如果它使我的应用程序崩溃，那么它也会使我的应用程序崩溃。
它永远都不应该，所以我想在开发中找到，
而没有所有这些代码，则代码更干净
还有ViewBuilder的东西。
我可能要做的另一件事是移动此感叹号
从这里我经过这个变种
到这里我实际上得到了这个var的价值。
因此，获取该firstIndex，
并立即强行打开包装。
这就是这个索引变量
转换为Int，我们可以直接将其传递。
好吧，那里还有一个地方
我们使用firstIndex的地方。
那是在我们的模型中，所以让我们来看一下
看看我们造成的损害
通过在此处切换到firstIndex。
在这里，我们将使用一些不同的策略
避免必须解开Optional的错误
我要在我的租赁前使用if
这是一个非常酷的功能。
只需将if放在前面，然后再放大括号
做任何你想做的事。
而您想要的任何事情只会实际发生
如果这个东西返回非零。
如果返回nil，则该代码甚至都不会执行。
在这里，请注意，如果让我们继续
冒号Int作为selectedIndex的类型。
顺便说一下，我们并不需要它，因为它可以推断出它，
但selectedIndex实际上是一个Int。
只有在firstIndex的情况下它才会实际存在
返回非nil，这是唯一的时间
该代码也将被执行。
但这正是我们想要的。
它可以保护我们免受selectedIndex的影响。
这意味着选择什么都不做。
如果我们在卡中找不到该卡，
那么这什么也没做。
这正是我们想要的。
我们希望它什么也不做。
让我们运行并确保此可选业务
没有破坏任何东西。
开始了。
是的，我们仍然可以将卡片翻转过来。
面朝上，面朝下。
但是现在，该尝试玩游戏了。
我们还需要Optional。
我们将尽力使这些卡
实际上会匹配，也许匹配的卡
从游戏中消失。
那也很酷。
那么我们该怎么做呢？
我们如何玩我们的游戏，让它玩？
好吧，我们需要一些设计。
我们是软件设计师。
我们必须从概念上思考
我们将如何实现这一目标。
因此，在我看来，我将经历各种情况。
首先，我所有的卡都是正面朝下的。
然后我点击卡片。
然后没有匹配发生。
卡只是面朝上翻转，这就是它的作用
现在就在我们的代码中。
所以，好的。
第二种状态是我拿到一张卡
然后我点击第二张卡片
好吧，那时候我真的很需要比赛。
因此，如果有一张卡片正面朝上
然后点击了卡片
那就是我要玩游戏的时候。
如果现在有两张卡片正面朝上，而我按了第三张卡片，
现在我基本上需要转向
其他两张卡片正面朝下。
无论他们是否匹配，
他们需要面朝下。
我刚刚接触过的卡片
那将是面朝上的。
在这三种情况下。
这就是所有场景。
在这三种情况下，我唯一一次玩过
一个匹配的游戏是如果有一张且只有一张卡片面朝上
当时我碰到一张新卡。
所以我需要发现这种情况
当只有一个。
所以我要去一个变种
跟踪索引
一张唯一的面朝上的卡片。
这是我数组的索引，
因此它将成为一个Int。
但这可能是我比赛的开始
而且没有面朝上的卡，
也许有两张面朝上的卡。
因此，这确实需要是可选的。
请注意，我在这里没有得到错误提示
我还没有初始化这个。
没有错误，但是我还没有初始化。
没有错误。
那是因为所有可选项
自动初始化为nil。
因此等于nil。
您可以根据需要输入。
但是，如果您不把它放在那儿，它就会在那里。
这很有道理，对吗？
可选值等于nil表示未设置。
从总体上讲，此var开始时未设置游戏。
因此，让我们继续前进。
我得到了这个selectedIndex，我真的只想要
要注意显然在我的阵列中的卡片，
而且还没有面朝上。
如果某张卡已经面朝上并且我点击了它，
我只是忽略它。
现在，您会认为这可行，对吗？
在此处获取selectedIndex，
并且selectedIndex不是朝上的。
但它抱怨selectedIndex尚未解决。
因此，如果您想这样做
你在说如果放手
然后你想做，在那件事上，
而不是在这里，您将使用逗号。
所以逗号就像顺序的
它首先在哪里做。
然后，完成了它，可以做到这一点，并设置了selectedIndex。
您甚至可以拥有更多这些，
就像我可能也想忽略Cards
这表明索引不匹配。
所以我只会碰卡
面朝上，无与伦比。
否则，我将忽略这些卡。
如果让我们使用这些逗号表示，则相当多。
在里面，我知道我已经选择了卡片
那是面朝下且尚未匹配的。
所以我只想看看是否只有一个
卡片正面朝上，所以我要说
如果我可以让potentialMatchIndex
等于indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard，
现在我可能有一场比赛
因为只有一张面朝上的卡。
我刚把另一张卡翻了过来。
我们需要尝试并匹配它。
没问题，如果在selectedIndex的Cards，
如果有内容，请记住内容
在卡上，这就是卡上的内容，
等于卡的潜在匹配数内容，
然后woohoo，有一场比赛。
现在，这使错误发生了。
为什么会出错？
它说：“二元运算符等于-不能应用
“到两个CardContent操作数。”
嗯，实际上这两个都是CardContent类型。
那是我们不在乎。
为什么我们不能在CardContent上做equals-equals？
这是一个字符串，对，表情符号字符串。
等等
这是一种通用的记忆游戏玩法。
这些里面没有表情符号。
他们是CardContent，这对我们来说不在乎。
可以是任何东西，图像，字符串，整数，等等。
我们试图说等于。
如果它是字符串，那么就可以了。
如果是图片怎么办？
您能说一张图片等于另一张图片吗？
也许不是，我不知道。
等于不是什么
那只适用于一切。
实际上，平等在Swift中如何工作？
不管您信不信，Swift中的equals-equals并不是内置的
语言。
它在Swift中使用了一种称为运算符的功能
这样您就可以关联一个运算符
具有功能。
这正是平等所要做的。
它将它与类型函数equals-equals关联。
现在，等于等于看起来很有趣
Swift中的功能。
这有点好笑，但也请记住
那张笑脸，表情符号笑脸，
在Swift中是有效的函数名称。
几乎所有Unicode字符都是有效的Swift。
因此，等于笑脸和笑脸一样有效。
所以这个等值函数是一个类型函数，
它只需要两个参数，
这是平等两边的两件事，
无论是否相同，它都会返回布尔值。
就是这样，这正是您所期望的。
但是，并非每种类型都具有“等于”。
只有某些类型可以实际
检查是否相等。
但幸运的是，等于函数
在一项名为“平等”的协议中，
所以我们可以在这里利用我们的约束和收获
说我们的CardContent在哪里实现Equatable。
换句话说，我们只会工作，
我们的MemoryGame仅在CardContent时有效
可以等于等于，可以等于。
让我们在文档中查看该协议。
所以我要做选择，单击。
这是有关它的顶级文档，
但让我们进入文档。
平等是一个非常重要的协议。
您可以看到很多解释
说某事物相等意味着什么
其他的东西，可转让财产，所有这一切。
但是当您找到有关它的功能列表时，
只有一个是必需的。
您看到这个要求了吗？
这意味着它是协议的一部分，
而且没有默认实现
扩展到任何地方，所以您必须实现它。
这就是我所说的，静态的，类型函数
这需要其中两件事，
记得在幻灯片中，我们拥有的比
而且你有自我，所以论点大于
与一个int或它是总统。
这里也是一样。
如果您有equals-equals，如果我们使用String，
那么Self和Self将是String和String，
因此它需要两个String并进行比较。
如果是Int，则需要两个Int，无论如何。
这是您必须实现的唯一功能。
真正简单的功能，简单易懂的功能，
尽管您必须阅读所有这些内容以确保
你真的很明白
这是我们必须在Equatable中实施的唯一方法。
所有其他这些都不是必需的
因为您可以通过扩展免费获得它们。
Swift Foundation为您提供了这些东西
元组和其他东西自动在这里。
不等于，它免费提供给您。
它们全部基于此处的等值。
这是一个协议，等于协议。
因此，我们只是强迫或约束，
我们的CardContent（我们不在乎）要平等。
我们有点在意。
我们关心它是等值的，因此我们可以对其进行比较。
好吧，如果这两件事匹配，
那我就说他们相配了
selectedIndex，isMatched处的纸牌等于true。
当然，在potentialMatchIndex的卡片
事实证明这是一场比赛，
因此它的isMatched也等于true。
因此，这些卡是匹配的。
棒极了。
请注意，无论它们是否匹配，
现在有两张卡片正面朝上。
因此，一张唯一的朝上卡的索引为nil。
没有一张，只有一张面朝上的卡。
有两个，所以这意味着零。
那其他情况呢？
因此，在这种情况下，没有一张，只有一张面朝上的卡。
因此，要么为零，要么不止一个。
在这种情况下，我们想将所有卡面朝下
除了我们当然选择的那个。
所以我们要做一些循环
在我们的cards.indices中索引
而且我们只需要购买每张卡
isFaceUp等于false，我们将确保
我们将Card设为true，将其面朝上。
在这种情况下也请注意
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard是我们的selectedIndex。
因为我只是把所有这些面朝下
我要把这个放回去
因此它将成为唯一的面朝上的卡片。
就是这样了。
这是我们的逻辑。
我们不需要选择此卡就可以在那里打印。
这就是完成这项工作的全部。
因此，让我们运行，看看我们的游戏是否按照我们的意愿进行。
好吧，这个游戏原来是最简单的游戏之一
进行记忆游戏，因为所有卡都面朝上。
所以，那不好。
让我们回到这里的模型
并进行更改，使所有卡面朝下开始。
我认为这将使游戏更具挑战性。
好吧，让我们尝试一下。
鬼，是的。
南瓜，哦，不，没有对手。
鬼，是的，蜘蛛，不，不，不再。
南瓜啊，我想我知道南瓜在哪里。
就在这里
是。
然后蜘蛛呢？
哦，现在请注意，它确实使我匹配的卡片面朝下，
如果我尝试触及它们，
我目前正在反复点击这些
他们不回头，因为他们已经匹配。
我们将忽略已经匹配的卡片。
但是拥有这些正面朝下的卡片并不是一个很好的用户界面
您无法触摸，它什么也没做。
我真的很想把这些拿走。
因此，如果它们匹配，我将带走它们。
因此，让我们回到我们的UI并执行此操作。
这是我们的CardView。
这是卡正面朝上的地方，那里没有问题。
这是他们面朝下的地方。
我要说的是如果卡片不匹配，
那我画
但是如果它匹配并且面朝下，
我什么也不会画。
同样，这是ViewBuilder。
这些简单的ifs。
您甚至可以将这些if嵌套在else中
或其他if的if内。
嵌套ifs可以。
请注意，我们在这里甚至不需要其他。
ViewBuilder知道如何处理事实
如果没有发生，那么这里什么也不会发生。
本质上是一个空的视图。
实际上，在SwiftUI中，有一个名为EmptyView的视图。
这就是这个ViewBuilder要做的
如果卡片朝下，则为ZStack。
看看是否可以解决该问题。
然后我们得到南瓜，蜘蛛，鬼魂。
哦，有比赛了，准备好了吗？
哇，这把他们带走了。
另一场比赛，带走了那些。
好的，这很好。
我们的游戏基本上运行良好。
因此，我想对模特做最后一件事。
我有点担心我有这种状态，
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard，
我必须保持同步
我对卡的更改。
这是一种容易出错的编程方式
当您在两个地方拥有州时。
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard在这里，
也可以从这些卡中确定
因此，让我们在这里使用计算的var
并从卡中获取indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard。
而且我们还将在这里进行一组
这样，如果有人设置indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard，
我们将所有其他卡片正面朝下。
这是您第一次看到计算属性
我们可以得到的价值，
但我们也可以设置
让我们先设置一个。
两者比较简单。
当有人时我们将如何反应
设置indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard的值？
那么在这种情况下，我们需要经历
我们所有的卡。
我将在这里浏览我们的索引。
而且我要把所有卡片都朝下放置。
除了我不想那样做
如果这是你说的
是indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard。
在此集合内，有一个名为newValue的特殊变量。
所以我可以告诉你索引是否等于newValue，
这个人说这等于的价值，
然后面朝上。
所以newValue是特殊的var，
仅在此集合内显示计算属性。
这就是人们设定的目标。
可能是零。
此newValue是可选的，因此可以为nil。
索引是一个整数，并且整数从不等于
未设置的可选
所以这等于是真的
如果这是可选的
及其关联的整数与此整数匹配
设置就这样，非常简单。
怎么样呢？
好吧，要获得它，我真的需要查看所有卡片
看看哪些面朝上
看看是否只有一个。
因此，让我们从获取所有面朝上的卡开始。
所以我要说faceUpCardIndices。
这将是一个整数数组。
顺便说一句，我要在这里使用这种语法
表示整数数组。
这与Int数组完全相同。
我要说的是在现实世界中
实际上，这是首选语法。
并非100％确信，但在我看来确实如此
人们更喜欢这种方法而不是Int数组。
我喜欢整数数组。
显然，这是通用的，
不管是Int还是所有
但是使用数组非常普遍，
所以我可以理解那里的速记。
那么，现在我该如何获得这个faceUpCardIndices？
它从那里开始是空的，
所以我要去找卡片索引。
遍历我所有的卡。
如果某个索引的卡面朝上，
然后我将其放入faceUpCardIndices中，
追加该索引。
好吧，现在我有了所有面朝上的Card索引。
我要说的是，如果faceUpCardIndices.count等于1，
因此只有一张卡，
然后我将那个faceUpCardIndices归零。
顺便说一句，还有一个不错的小变种，
首先。
当我们先输入时
请注意，此变量的返回类型，
或此var的类型是Int，问号，
可选Int，为什么？
因为数组可能为空。
因此，如果您说Array.first，而Array为空，
这将返回nil。
Swift使用Optionals进行交流。
否则，我将返回nil。
因为如果没有一张卡
在面朝上的卡片列表中，那么显然，
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard为零，仅此而已。
所以现在计算出来
我不必太努力地确保它保持同步。
例如，在这里，我什至不必说
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard为零。
完全删除该代码
因为它总是会知道
当有两个面朝上的卡片时。
它计算它。
有点类似，因为我在这里
唯一的一张面朝上的卡片就是该索引，
我不需要将所有其他部件正面朝下放置。
这将由设置者自动完成。
而且，将其面朝上的确如此，
我们只需要在这里做，因为再次
设置indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
将确保此selectedIndex朝上。
因此，这使得该代码非常少
玩整个纸牌配对游戏。
现在，这里要花很多代码。
我们将在一秒钟内解决该问题，
但请确保这没有破坏任何内容。
开始了。
南瓜，蜘蛛，蜘蛛，蜘蛛，南瓜，好吧。
鬼，不，南瓜，鬼，鬼，鬼，南瓜。
所以这是工作。
漂亮的代码就在这里。
这里的代码多于我们所需的代码。
那么，如何才能减少此代码呢？
在这里，我只能想到一件事
使它更有效率，
这是我在说的是真的
然后将其设置为true，否则将其设置为false。
我可以把它放到这里。
然后，我不需要所有这些开销
这一切的语法如果。
所以我要设置每张卡。
除非索引，否则我将其设置为false
等于那个人所说的等于，
就像我在这里做。
很好。
那是最少的代码。
那怎么办
信不信由你，我要做到
所以这是一行代码。
您知道我们喜欢此类中的一行代码。
您的第一次家庭作业证明了这一点。
那么我该如何编写这一行代码？
我将从这里拥有所有这些开始
成为一行，我要做
具有称为过滤器的范围内的功能。
所以我要拿我的卡指数，这是一个范围
在零，点点之间，小于cards.count。
并调用此函数过滤器。
您会在此处看到过滤器。
它返回一个整数数组。
您在这里在左侧看到整数数组。
这些整数就是这个范围内的所有整数
该函数需要一个Int
并返回布尔值，则返回true。
所以看起来像这样。
让我们双击这个。
这里是。
我什至可以双击它。
它为我填补了。
这是一个函数，一个内联函数，
需要一个Int并返回一个Bool。
我们应该返回是否包含此Int，
这是指数之一
在结果faceUpCardIndices中。
我们通过过滤掉其他阵列来制作一个新的阵列。
这就是索引，因此我们将其称为索引。
我们想做什么？
我们想说该索引处的归还卡片，
点是isFaceUp。
这就是我们想要做的。
当然，我们希望在Swift中减少代码量，
这样我们就可以收回这个回报。
也许我们会像这样把它放在这里。
我们可以推断出此返回类型。
不需要那个，也不需要这些括号。
我上次没有给你看的另一件事
我们可以做得更小，
这是参数在这里指定
带索引。
您可以摆脱它，而只需使用零美元，
每个参数分别为1美元和2美元。
第一个参数为零美元，
第二个论点一美元等等。
所以我们快到了。
这一切都就在这里。
因为我们现在只需一口气计算一下，
我们在这里得到这个警告
现在可以放手了。
这个怎么样？
我们如何摆脱这一点？
这里发生了什么？
在这里，我们实际上只是对索引数组说，
如果只有你们一个，把它给我。
否则，请给我零。
好吧，为什么我们不扩展Array，
使用扩展数组，有一个这样做的var？
因为这似乎是一个合理的数组问题。
嘿Array先生，只给我自己一件事，
否则给我零。
因此，让我们在这里为Array创建另一个扩展。
做一个Swift文件。
我们称其为Array + Only
因为它返回数组中的唯一内容。
而对Array的扩展将扩展所有Array。
对Array的这种扩展不是这样的
元素可识别的位置。
这个扩展到所有数组。
它将添加此变量，我仅会调用。
类型为元素，问号，可选元素。
它是经过计算的，它只返回数组的计数
等于一个，第一个，冒号，零。
因此这在Array中，因此count是Array的计数。
如果那等于一，
我们在这里使用这个三元运算符
返回数组中的第一项。
否则为零。
超级简单，那超级简单的代码
使一切都在这里消失。
我们不需要任何这些。
相反，我们可以在这里只说点
并摆脱所有这些。
只需退货。
但是，由于现在这是单线的，所以我们不需要退货。
我们甚至可以在这里将其全部变成一行
也这样
这段代码突然变得紧凑了很多。
因此，请确保我们没有在此处破坏任何内容。
单击，是的，哦，是的，它有效。
现在，这已经为您的作业设置了精美的外观。
您现在要使用此工作游戏
并对其进行一些增强。
因此，请查看相关内容。
我们下次见。
-[旁白]有关更多信息，请访问stanford.edu。
(gentle music)
- [Narrator] Stanford University.
- [Instructor] We are back, lecture four.
Stanford CS193p, spring of 2020.
Today, I'm going to start
off with a big demo,
and it's going to be to make our card game
be in rows and columns, instead
of all across in one row,
which is gonna make our
game a lot better, no doubt,
but it's also gonna be
a super good example
of doing generics with protocols,
and also functions as types.
And we're gonna learn more
about being a container View
because we're gonna build our own
rows and columns container
View for our cards.
After that demo, we're gonna
hop back into the slides here.
We're gonna talk more about
the Swift type systems,
specifically the type enum.
And then after that, we're
gonna continue in the slides
and talk about one of
the most important types
in all of Swift, Optional,
which happens to be an enum.
And Optional is so
important that I'm gonna go
right back into a demo after that
and show you two really important examples
of using an Optional to
design your code in Swift.
So, let's get started with that demo.
All right, well, it's type
to fix this major deficiency
in our game, which is
that all of the cards
are in one row,
and we know that we could
much more efficiently
use this space if we had rows and columns.
We're gonna do that by
replacing our HStack here
with a Grid.
Now as of the taping of this class,
there was no such thing
as a Grid in SwiftUI,
so we're gonna have to write that.
And it actually provides
us with a great opportunity
to learn a lot about how
things like ZStack work.
So, ZStack we know takes
this argument right here,
which is a function.
This curly brace means it's a function.
It's a function that takes no arguments,
unlike for example, ForEach,
its function to create a View
takes an argument.
But ZStack, the View that gets built here
is quite powerful.
It could be a list of other Views.
It could be a if-then,
a combination thereof.
So this particular function that can build
these complicated View
is called a ViewBuilder.
And we're not gonna use
ViewBuilder quite yet.
We'll eventually learn about ViewBuilder.
So our Grid is just
gonna have a simple View
that it's going to
replicate using a ForEach,
exactly the same way as a ForEach,
to put a certain View at every spot
in the row and column.
So our Grid is really going
to combine HStack like Grid,
except for 2D HStack if
you wanna think of it,
with ForEach like this.
We're gonna take an Array
of Identifiable things,
like these Cards, and then
we're going to pass a function
that takes one of the Identifiable
things as its argument,
and returns the View to use
to draw at that location in the Grid.
Very simple here.
So let's go create that View.
We're gonna go over here to New, File.
We're gonna put it in its own
file because this is really
a very powerful reusable object.
We could use it in all our
apps that needed a Grid.
So it is a SwiftUI View,
so I'm gonna click there.
I'm gonna call it Grid.
Gonna double-check that
it's in one of these
yellow folders here and that this content
kinda matches that, and
it does, so we're good.
And here's our Grid, and of
course, we get "Hello, World!"
This code down here, you'll
remember, at the bottom
is to hook us up to our canvas over here.
But this Grid is completely generic.
And so, if we were gonna
make this preview work,
we would need to come up
with some test data for it.
And we're not gonna do that in this demo,
but someday in the future,
maybe you could do it
as an exercise.
But if you ever delete
this and need it back,
it'll say Create Preview
here in your canvas.
All right, so we gotta
get started on Grid.
First thing we're gonna
do is its two arguments.
The first argument is this
Array of Identifiable,
and the second argument is this function
that takes one of the
Identifiables and provides a View.
So let's get those two
arguments there as vars.
So the first var is I'll call
it items, an Array of Item.
And this Item for us in
Grid is a don't-care.
We really don't-care what that thing is.
It could be anything.
It's gonna be a Card over
here, but there's no reason
for it to be any particular thing,
so it's a don't-care for us.
And similarly, that second argument,
viewForItem I'll call
it, that's a function.
It's a function that takes
an Item as the argument,
and it returns some ItemView,
which is another don't-care for us.
We really don't-care what
kind of View you provide
for each item, so that's
a don't-care, ItemView.
Good start, and we could actually
get this going over here.
Unfortunately, we have to
name this items right there.
This one is really viewForItem,
and put that right there.
But this is the last
argument to this function,
so we know that when the last argument
to a function is another function,
then we can just get rid of
that label, close it off,
and have our function
kinda float on the outside.
So this is the last argument to our Grid.
And that is both of its vars,
this one and the viewForItem.
Just like when we called CardView here,
we had to initialize its
vars as this one Card var,
same thing here with Grid.
We're initializing its two vars.
This might be a good time
to talk about how is it
that ForEach doesn't have
to have this label items?
When we had ForEach, it just
had the iteratable thing
that had Identifiables in it.
How come it didn't have an argument?
Well, it's using technology
that you know well to do that.
So let's do it in Grid as well,
which is it's just an init.
So normally you might
have your init say items
is an Array of Item,
viewForItem is a function
that takes an Item and
returns some ItemView.
That would be a normal kind of init.
And in here, you just want to
initialize your vars, like items.
Well, that's equal to the
Items that are passed in.
And then viewForItem, that's
equal to the viewForItem
that's passed in.
By the way, Swift is gonna
be very confused here
because it doesn't know
which items this is
and which items this is.
We've got a local argument to
this function called items,
and then we have a property called items.
So you can easily fix
Swift's confusion here
by saying self.items,
and self.viewForItem.
This is a different reason
to have to put self here
than we saw with the explicit
self blah-blah-blah hit fix.
But it makes sense here, right?
By doing self.items, now
Swift knows that we're talking
about the green one,
and that this one must be the black one.
Now, this allows us to put this under-bar
as the external name.
Remember under-bar is external name
means do not provide an external name,
and that's exactly what's going on here.
And if I rebuild, you're gonna see
that this code over here, perfectly fine.
However, we still have a
problem back here in our Grid.
This error right here.
It says, "Assigning non-escaping parameter
"'viewForItem' to an @escaping closure."
So I'm gonna try and explain
this escaping closure
in just a few minutes.
Normally, I would actually
probably have slides on it.
I'm gonna skip that this
quarter because in SwiftUI,
since we're doing functional programming,
almost everything is a value type,
and the problem that this
escaping closure thing
is trying to address here
really, really rare in SwiftUI.
Happened a lot more when we
had object-oriented programming
in UIkit.
So, here's what's going on.
This function that's passed in here
that creates a View for a given item
is not actually used in this initializer.
We salt it away into a
var and call it later.
We're gonna call it down here in our body
when we need to actually create the Views
for all of our Items.
So, we have to mark this
kind of function, @escaping.
You can think of it as this function
is going to escape from this initializer
without getting called.
Now, Swift has to be careful,
and it's actually very powerful
and knows how to deal with these functions
that might get called later.
Why can that be an issue?
Well, let's look back
here where we actually
pass this function in.
Whatever code is in here has
to be able to be called later.
So if we use any variables,
especially if we use
a local variable or
something from this function,
that has to be around in the future
when this function gets executed.
Now, how does Swift
accomplish this wonderful feat
of keeping everything in
here around until the future?
Well, it does this by
making function types
be reference types.
Just like classes, our
ViewModel are reference types,
they live in the heap.
They're stored in memory.
People have pointers to them.
Same thing with these functions
that can be called later.
They live in the heap and
they have pointers to them.
Now, the things inside of here
might also live in the heap.
If any of the things in here
are classes, for example,
then the self in here
is gonna be a pointer
to something in the heap.
And the problem we're trying
to avoid here in Swift
is having self have some var in it
that actually points to this function
because we know this function
points to self inside here.
They're both gonna be in the heap.
The function's kept in the heap
because it's gonna be executed later.
All the things inside the
function have be kept in the heap
so that it will properly execute later.
And so if anything in here points back,
we've got a situation where
two things in the heap
are pointing to each other.
And the way that Swift cleans up memory
is when nobody points
to something anymore,
it cleans up the memory and frees it up
for someone else to use.
Well, if two things are
pointing to each other
and they're both in the heap,
they're never gonna be able to go away
because they're always gonna
have a pointer to each other.
That's called a memory cycle.
So, this whole thing is to try to make it
so that we can detect memory cycles
by seeing these escaping functions.
Amazingly, this is also why you
get this warning about self.
You know when we don't
put a self-dot in here
in our onTapGesture function,
we're gonna get this error that says
this requires explicit self
to make the capture semantics explicit.
Capture semantics means
the fact that it's going
to capture everything in here,
inside this onTapGesture's function,
and keep it in the heap
so that when onTapGesture
executes it in the future when
someone taps on this Card,
that this stuff is still around.
Well if you look at this code,
you're thinking, "Oh well, I
guess it captures ViewModel,"
but it actually would
have to capture self.
So it makes you type the self
so that you realize, oh yes,
this function is going to
make self be in memory.
And then you can verify
that self doesn't actually
somehow directly or
indirectly come back around
and point to this function,
which it doesn't do in
this case because in here,
our ViewModel never points to our Views.
Views point to the ViewModel
but not backwards direction,
so it's no problem.
But even more it's no
problem because this self-dot
does not live in the heap anyway.
This self-dot is this
struct, self is this struct.
Structs are value types.
They don't live in the heap.
So, this is not necessary anyway.
And that is the fix that
has been publicly approved,
that you're probably gonna
see a couple of months
after this video is made.
So this is gonna be out of
date quickly, this video.
But the fix is basically
if self, in this case,
inside of one of these escaping functions
is gonna be held around in the heap,
if self doesn't live in the heap,
in other words, it's a value
type, a struct or an enum,
then you don't need to
have this error come up
and warn you, "Hey, put self-dot there
"so you make sure you
don't have a memory cycle
"where self points to this function,
"this function points to self."
That can't happen because
there aren't two things
in the heap that could point to each other
because self is a struct.
It's a value type, does
not live in the heap.
So, there you got just a
little quick explanation
of all this escaping, and
you even understand now
what this self-dot is.
If you don't understand
all of things I just said
about these escaping
functions and this self-dot,
really, I don't think you have
to worry about it that much
for a couple reasons.
One, this week's reading,
you're gonna read
about these closures, these functions
that are in-line that
capture the stuff they need
to be able to execute later.
So when you read that,
maybe you'll understand it.
Of course, you always have the option,
go on the class forums, ask
more about it to clarify.
And finally, with SwiftUI,
it's just not that important
because so many of the
self-dots are just value types.
Everything in the View, for
example, is all value types.
Our ViewModel, it's a class.
It has possibilities.
But since the ViewModel
never points to anything
in the View, we never really have to worry
about anything in the View
creating these memory cycles.
It'd be very rare.
It's possible to do, but very, very rare.
So the bottom line is I
don't think you have to worry
about it that much.
The only thing that's gonna bother you
is that you're always
gonna have to put self-dot
in front of these things,
or you're gonna have
to deal with this error
and do this, click on
it, and fix all the time.
Again, that's something
you're only gonna have to do
till the beta of this
public thing comes out,
and hopefully, in a couple of months.
But, at worst, a few months.
And after that, then you
won't have to worry about this
at all because not putting self here
when self is a value type will
not generate this warning.
That is the proposed fix.
All right, that's enough of that aside.
This all started because
we had this warning
that told us we had to put escaping here
because indeed, this function
does escape from this init
because we put it in this var.
Let's do our body.
Our body's not "Hello, World!" obviously.
Our body is actually quite simple.
It's just a ForEach of all of our Items.
And for each of our Items,
we are going to return
a viewForItem of that Item.
We're gonna call our function viewForItem.
This is a var, that's a
function we're gonna call it.
And of course, we wanna ForEach.
It also has an escaping
function there for the View,
so we have to say self-dot.
This creates some errors for
us, so let's look at these.
The first one says, "Cannot
convert value of type
"Array of Item to expected
argument type 'Range of Int'."
Oh no, we saw this exact argument problem
when we were over here doing
ForEach the first time.
We were passing this Array of Cards
and we were like, oh, I
thought I could do that.
We used to pass zero dot dot less than for
and we went to Array,
and I had told you that
this ForEach takes an Array.
But we learned that it was an Array
only of Identifiable things.
So we have the same exact problem here.
This ForEach of this
items has to be an Array
of Identifiable things.
Well, that's a problem for us
because Item is a don't-care.
We have no idea what this thing is.
But here is where we get
constrains and gains into the act.
We're gonna say where
Item is Identifiable.
So now we've created
a Grid that only works
with this don't-care when that
don't-care is Identifiable.
So this can still be anything.
But it has to be Identifiable.
This is what I was talking
about in the slides,
a care-a-little-bit kind of thing.
We care a little bit about Item.
We care that it's Identifiable.
So now we have a different error here.
This ForEach error is saying,
"Return type of property
'body'," this is our body,
"requires that 'ItemView'
conform to 'View'."
So what is ItemView?
That's the return type of this function.
And of course, that makes sense
because ForEach can only
use Views to have Views
for these items.
This has to be a View.
So, this viewForItem return
type here of ItemView,
it has to be a View.
And what type is it?
It's a don't-care as well.
We'll do the same thing here.
ItemView has to be a View.
You all seeing how we're
connecting generics,
this is a very generic struct
right here, with protocols.
These are protocols, and
we're using them to constrain
these don't-cares to work.
The next thing we have to do
here is we're a container.
Grid contains all these Views.
It puts them in rows and columns.
It contains them.
And we know the container's
job is to take the space
that's offered to them and divide it up
amongst the things inside.
That means we need to
figure out how much space
has been allocated to us.
And we know how to do that.
That's GeometryReader.
Okay, GeometryReader.
Geometry in is going to allow us
to find out how much space
was given to the Grid,
which we're then going to
hand off to these guys.
So, put this in here.
Now, as soon as put it in here,
of course we're gonna get the
self-dot problem with items.
I'm gonna use the same
solution I used last time,
which is I'm gonna
create a func here called
body(for size: CGSize).
It's gonna return some View of course.
I'm gonna put my code
for my body inside here.
And here I'm just gonna do a
self.body(for: geometry.size).
Again, this is just purely to make it
so I don't have to do
self-dot inside this body.
Just like GeometryReader is escaping
and so we did this self.body,
ForEach is also escaping,
and so I'm gonna do the same thing here.
self.body(for item, in size).
I'm gonna move this to
another little func
body(for item, in size)
turn some View.
And now I don't need the self-dot here.
Just return that.
So, we've arranged our code nicely here.
All we have left to do, believe it or not,
is to actually offer these
Views some of our space,
and then to position them.
That's what containers do.
Offer space, and they position.
To do this, we need to do some math
because we've been offered this space,
and now we need to divide
it up by however many items
we have here.
And to do that math, I
actually wrote some code
that I gave you, and we're gonna use here.
Let's drag it in.
By the way, when you drag code in,
be sure to do this Copy items if needed.
That's almost always what you want.
You want a copy of that
code to put in your project.
Otherwise, it's going to be
referring to your desktop
or wherever you dragged it from.
All right, so we finished that.
So here let's take a look at this little.
This is the math, this GridLayout.
The math, it does this calculation,
so let's take a look.
Now I've collapsed the init
and this two var and func here
'cause we're not gonna look at
the implementation of these.
I do encourage you, after this lecture,
to go and take a look
at the implementation,
and see if you can figure it out.
You'll need the rest of this
lecture to have the knowledge
to be able to really
understand what this is doing,
but it's a good exercise to
try and understand this thing.
It's only about 10 lines of code,
so you shouldn't have
too much trouble with it.
But here's what a GridLayout does.
Its initializer takes a
number of items and a size,
and it divides that
size up by those items.
It does exactly what Grid wants.
Now, it also even lets you
specify a desired aspect ratio.
It can't guarantee that, but
it can try and get close to it.
And that's it, we just create
a GridLayout that does that.
Then we have a var here
that will tell us the size
of the items that are all the same size,
so this would be the size.
And then also the location
of each item as a point.
This is the center of each item,
which again, exactly what Grid wants.
So GridLayout was definitely
made with Grid in mind,
but it's pretty much a
generic divider-up of CGSize
by a certain number of items.
So, let's create this GridLayout
by calling this initializer right here.
I'm gonna do it up in my GeometryReader.
In fact, I'm gonna change
this passing of the size
to instead pass a GridLayout.
And the itemCount is
just the number of Items
that we have.
This is our items Array
right here, its count.
And I'm gonna skip the
desired aspect ratio thing.
We'll just use whatever the default is.
Hopefully in your reading,
you saw that you can have
default arguments for functions
and GridLayout uses that.
But you do have to have the size,
and this is of course going
to be in geometry.size.
And we're still inside
of GeometryReader here
so this items is gonna
have to be self.items.
It's an instance variable there.
So, I've changed this body(for).
Instead of body for size, it's
now our body for the layout.
GridLayout here.
And same thing, I'm gonna
have to pass this on through,
so this is now body(for:
item, in: layout).
So that makes this a layout as well,
passing it on down along the line.
And now we're in here,
we've got this layout,
and we've laid it out with the
number of Items in our size.
So we can easily do things like
offer space to these Views,
which we do with frame.
So we're gonna say frame's width
is the layout's itemSize.width,
and the frame's height is
the layout.itemSize.height.
We're gonna offer the same little subspace
of our space to each of the items.
That's what itemSize in GridLayout does.
Again, GridLayout was
created with this many items
in the size that was offered to us.
That's how we divided it up.
And then we have to position the View,
so we do that with position.
That's the function we do it with.
And we're gonna position
it at the layout's location
ofItemAt index.
So this is indexed, just like
we had with our Cards in fact.
So we have to find the index of this Item
in our Item Array.
No problem, we kinda know how to do that.
We'll say let index equal,
mm, I know how to do this.
I'm gonna create a function
on my self index of this Item.
And I'm gonna go down here
and say func index (of item).
And it's gonna return an
Int, an index into the Array.
We'll return zero here first,
and then we'll fill it out in a second.
Now, this is gonna confuse
Swift again a little bit
'cause you've got index,
this local variable,
and then index, this function.
So, we can fix that
again, same way, self-dot.
Now it knows this index is the function,
and this index is a local
variable we're creating.
So, we do actually use self-dot.
Even once they make that
change with the value type
self-dots not being flagged like that,
we still sometimes wanna use self-dot
to define the difference between
something that's a property
or a function versus a local variable
or a parameter to the function.
All right, in index here, how
are we gonna find this Item
in the Array?
Well, guess what?
These Items are Identifiable.
And probably some of you are like,
"Hmm, this seems awfully familiar."
Well yeah, we're gonna do for index
in zero dot dot less than items.count
that we have.
And if the items at that [index].id
equals this Item's id,
then we're going to return that index.
Otherwise we're gonna return zero,
which is just as bogus as it
was the last time we did this.
Okay now, this function
is kinda double bogus.
It's bogus in that we're
still doing this return zero.
In other words, if we can't find the item
in our items, well, we'll
just return the first item,
index zero right there.
That's bogus.
But what's also bogus is that
this code is exactly the same,
yes, as this code over here in our Model.
So, man, you'd never wanna write
the exact same code like this twice.
That is just terrible programming.
Well, we're gonna fix that in a minute.
But first let's just
see if our Grid works.
Believe it or not, this is
all we need for our Grid.
There's nothing else.
So we get the space that's offered to us.
We use this GridLayout to divide it up,
and then we offer it to our
little sub-Views in there,
and then we position
them at those locations
in the GridLayout.
That's all that's required,
so let's take a run here.
See if it worked.
Ah, and it did.
Look at that, there's our six
cards not in a row anymore.
Let's go landscape, and
look, it resized the cards
to fit the space better.
Now, I would like a little bit of padding
between the cards, but
that's a matter back here
of when we create our CardViews,
we can just put a little padding on there.
If we put some padding
around these CardViews
inside of our Grid,
huh, we get the padding.
Huh, works great.
Maybe we don't want quite so much padding.
Maybe we just want padding of five.
Run that.
Huh, that looks pretty darn good.
Okay well, now that our Grid is working,
let's go and fix the bogus
code that we have right here,
which is this index of item.
And it's bogus 'cause
this totally replicates
this other thing.
Let's think a little bit
about what's going on here.
What're we actually asking,
in both cases, to happen?
We have an Array of things
that are Identifiable,
and we have one of
those things, hopefully.
We know it's Identifiable as well.
And we want to look and
see if we can find it.
So, that sounds to be
more like an Array thing.
Let's add a function to
Array that does this.
Extension Array.
But only to Arrays where
the elements in the Array
are Identifiable.
So there it is again,
constrains and gains.
This extension only is
going to add this function
that we wanna add to those kind of Arrays.
And so, it's the same function.
In fact, I'm just gonna copy and paste
and we'll modify this,
or even cut and paste.
Cut that outta there.
Paste this in here.
It's not quite the same in here
because here we were looking at items.
Obviously this is an Array function,
so now items is self.
And same thing here.
It's not the items' count.
It's self's count.
And the type of this item,
index of item, it's not Item.
It's Element 'cause
that's what we're looking
at an Array of.
We have an Array whose
elements are all Identifiable
and what we're saying
here is get the index
of one of the elements of
this Array that's Identifiable
by looking it up.
Now, this is correct and
this does the right thing,
but I actually don't like the
naming that I've chosen here.
One thing about this is
it doesn't actually return
the index of this item.
It returns the first one that it finds.
Going through the Array from zero on up,
and when it finds one, it returns it.
So this is really the
first index of this item.
I also don't like the word item.
Item makes sense up here in Grid
because we have Item.
The word "item" is all over the place.
But really in Array, Item is not a thing.
There's Element, but there's no Item.
And really what this is is the first index
matching that Element.
So I'm gonna use firstIndex
matching as my name.
This feels more like an Array function,
firstIndex matching this Element.
So, how do we use that up here?
Instead of self.index of,
we're just gonna say items, the Array,
dot firstIndex matching the Item.
So we're asking the Array to do this now,
to go find the first
index matching this item.
And we can do exactly
the same thing over here.
We no longer even need this function.
We get it outta here because
we know that our Cards Array
right here can do firstIndex
matching the Card.
So we are reusing this code.
And look how small our Model has become.
It's tiny, it's hardly any code in here.
And some of that is because
we've just made Array
more powerful to look this thing up.
Same thing with Grid.
Grid's very small amount of code
because we're leveraging this Array.
Now, this Array thing has
nothing to do with Grid,
so it does not belong here in Grid.swift.
So I'm going to cut it out Grid.swift.
And I'm gonna put it in its own file.
It's not a SwiftUI View.
It's just a regular Swift file.
Now when we do extensions like this,
we usually call the file Array,
the thing we're extending,
plus some sort of descriptor
of what kind of thing this is.
And so, this is kind of Identifiable,
Array+Identifiable.
So let's go in here.
There it is.
Paste it in.
Notice that this is import Foundation,
which is perfectly fine.
This is not a UI thing.
This is purely Arrays and Identifiables.
None of those are UI things.
So we go back to Grid.
Do build here so it notices
this all this stuff.
And make sure that our Model
also is working, and it is.
No errors, in fact, no
errors in our whole program.
Let's run, make sure that our
Array is doing it, and it is.
All right, so once again, we
are using this whole concept
of constrains and gains.
Here we are constraining the
don't-care type of the Array
so that they're Identifiable,
and that allows us to gain this function.
For all Arrays where elements
are identified they get this.
No Arrays that don't have
Identifiable elements,
they don't even see this function.
Wouldn't even escape complete in Xcode.
It's not even there.
And we're doing the same thing
with constrains and gains here
to make it so that our
Grid is always a Grid
of Identifiable things, matching
two things that are Views.
That is it for this demo.
So I'm gonna go back to the slides,
and we're gonna fix this.
And we need the type in Swift
called Optional to do this,
a very, very important
type, which is an enum.
So let's do a quick
review of what enums are,
and then we'll talk about
this very important type, Optional.
Enums are just another
type like struct or class,
but in the case of an enum,
the value is discrete.
Good example here, FastFoodMenuItem
is either a hamburger
or it's fries or it's a
drink or it's a cookie.
It can't be anything else.
Gotta be one of those four things.
That's the only things on the menu,
and it has to be one and
only one of those things.
Enum, like a struct, is a value type.
Gets copied as you pass it around.
It does not live in the heap.
There's no pointers to it.
It's a value type.
Now what's cool about enums in Swift,
unlike most other languages,
is that each of the discrete values
can have some associated data with it
that's very specific to that
particular discrete value.
For example, we have hamburger here.
And if the FastFoodMenuItem's a hamburger,
we're gonna say how many patties?
Is this a double or a triple or single?
If it's fries, is this a
large fry, small fries?
If it's a drink, you'll see
there, you have this drink,
which is Coke or Dr. Pepper or whatever.
Notice that that String
is unnamed right there,
so these things don't have to have names.
This yellow syntax that you're seeing here
probably, hopefully, looks
familiar from your reading.
This is just a tuple.
So all the rules of tuples
which allow you to have labels
or not labels, and have as
many items as you want here,
all perfectly valid
as the associated data values right here.
So how do you set the value of an enum?
It's very simple.
You just say the name of the enum,
like FastFoodMenuItem,
dot, the discrete value,
hamburger or cookie, like here.
Now of course, in the case
where there's associated data,
you have to provide that associated data.
Hamburger(patties: 2) in this case.
There's no way for it
to create a hamburger
if it doesn't know how
many patties there are.
Now Swift can do type inference here
so that you don't have
to type FastFoodMenuItem
on both sides of this equals.
But you have to be a little bit careful.
You have to put it on
one side of the equals
because in the case if you just say
var yetAnotherItem equals cookie,
Swift does not have enough information
to infer that we're talking
about fast food menu items here.
It could be anything that has a cookie.
So you have to, somewhere,
FastFoodMenuItem has to appear
so that Swift can infer.
How do we check the value?
You might think it would be like an if.
You know, if this menu
item equals a hamburger,
then do something.
But we don't use if with enum.
We use this expression switch.
Now switch exists in other languages.
It's very powerful in Swift,
not only for checking enums
as you're going to see,
but it has regular expression matching
and all kinds of stuff.
Again, you read about that hopefully
in your reading assignment.
So if I wanna check
what value menuItem has,
I'm gonna switch on menuItem,
and then have a case statement
for every single possible menuItem.
And it has to be every single one.
Now, I'm not paying any attention here
to the associated data, and I'm
allowed to ignore that here.
I can still have case
FastFoodMenuItem.hamburger
print the word burger.
I can't say how many patties it is
'cause I haven't looked
at the associated data.
I'm gonna show you that in a second.
But I can still print
burger if I want here.
Swift can infer, of course,
that these are all fast food menu items,
so you don't have to say
case FastFoodMenuItem.hamburger
every time.
You can just switch on the menuItem.
Use .hamburger, .fries, .drink.
It knows menuItem is a
FastFoodMenuItem in this case.
By the way, switch requires you to cover
every single possible case.
So you might have a case, like hamburger,
that you don't care about.
You don't wanna print out hamburger.
In that case, you can just say break.
So, break breaks out of the switch,
and saying case .hamburger
break means it will do nothing
if the menu item is a hamburger.
Similarly, if you really only
care about a couple of cases
and all the rest, you could
just do some default behavior,
you can use the special keyword default.
So a default will happen
if you didn't list
a specific case for something.
But you have to do one or the other.
Either you have to have all the cases
and the ones you don't care
about you break out of,
or you can only have some of the cases,
but then you have to
provide this default case.
It's required in switch in general.
Not just for enums, but always in Swift,
switches require complete
and utter coverage
of all possibilities.
What about that associated data?
Well we can do that in switch as well.
We just add the stuff
you're seeing in yellow here
where when we say case .hamburger,
we say parentheses, let pattyCount.
And that is going to grab the
associated data with hamburger
and assign it to this little
very local variable pattyCount
that's only going to be valid
for this print statement
or whatever that's happening
after this hamburger.
Same thing with the fries.
And for example, the drink is interesting.
So the drink is going to grab
the brand and the ounces.
Notice that ounces used to have
a label when I declared it,
but I didn't do that here and that's okay
because this is tuples.
Tuples you can use the labels
if you want on both sides,
declaring and using it.
And so, this is the exact same
thing that's going on here
where the associated
value, you can grab it
however you want to grab it.
All right, let's see.
Methods, yes, you can
have methods on enums.
It's pretty much unlimited,
whatever you wanna do.
And properties, you can
have computed properties,
but you can't have any stored properties.
All the storage that goes with an enum
is only in these associated values,
which kinda makes sense 'cause
an enum is a discrete thing.
It really wouldn't make
sense to have other data
that applies to all of them.
That wouldn't be discrete.
So, this is why you have to do this.
Switching on self.
All right so, if you have
a function in your enum,
and it's supposed to
essentially tell you something
about the enum, which is really common
to have these kind of functions.
Here I have this function
isIncludedInSpecialOrder number,
which is gonna say whether
this FastFoodMenuItem
is included in a certain special order.
And to do that, I'm gonna
have to switch on myself
and see what I am, to see if I am included
in that special order.
So you can see I have a
bunch of examples here.
One of these examples I wanna
look at a little bit closer,
which is this drink example.
Notice that it's getting the
associated value in the switch
for the ounces, but it's ignoring
whether it's a Coke or Dr. Pepper.
We don't care.
It doesn't matter in terms
of whether it's included
in a special order.
So, this under-bar is the don't
pay any attention to this,
I'm not interested, essentially.
Just like when we have a function,
it has parameters that have external names
and internal names, we
use that under-bar to say
we're not interested in the
external name, don't use it.
That's what this means here as well.
So this is how if you
had some associated value
as a tuple that had multiple things,
you can just ignore some of them
when you're getting the values.
Enums can do constrains
and gains with protocols
just like structs and classes can.
There's a very interesting
protocol called CaseIterable.
CaseIterable, you gain
a var called allCases.
It's static var, so you
send it to the type,
like here, a TeslaModel.allCases
you see there.
And it's just going to return
to you an iterable thing,
something you can do for-in
over of all the cases.
And that can be super valuable.
In your assignment three,
it's likely that you're going
to need to use this.
Now that we know what an enum is,
we can talk about, probably,
the most important enum
in all of Swift, which is called Optional.
So, an Optional looks
essentially like this.
It's got two discrete values.
One is the case none,
and one is the case some.
And in the some case,
it has associated value,
which is a don't-care.
So, Optional, Optional
just works with any type.
It doesn't care what type it is.
So essentially, Optional is either
is an is set case, that's some,
or the not set case, that's the none.
And that's what an Optional is.
Essentially a type.
You're gonna have
variables of type Optional.
They're either gonna be set or not set.
And if they're set, they're
gonna have associated value
of some type, which Optional
doesn't care what type that is.
So where do we use Optional?
Well, you can imagine we use it any time
we have a variable whose value
could either be not set or
unspecified or undetermined,
anything like that.
What're some examples?
Well, that bogus return
type of firstIndex matching.
If the matching thing is not in the Array,
we're currently returning zero.
And that's the first element in the Array.
That's totally wrong.
So instead, we're gonna
have firstIndex matching's
return type be Optional.
It'll be an Optional with the
associated value being an Int.
And so it's either gonna
return set or not set.
It's gonna return set if it was able
and the associated
value will be the index.
Or it's gonna return not set,
the none case right there,
if it couldn't find that
matching thing in there.
Another good example
just of a normal variable
would be, let's say in my
matching game in the Model,
what if I had a variable which is like
the index of the currently face-up Card?
Okay well, when the game starts,
there is no face-up Card.
So what would that index be?
It's like, it's not set.
So we're gonna use an
Optional to store that.
That var is not gonna be
of type Int for the index.
It's gonna be of type Optional.
Now the associated value will be an Int
because of course, if it is set,
we wanna know what that Int is.
There's a couple good
examples which I'm gonna show
in the demo right after this.
So this happens surprisingly often
that you need some variable
that sometimes is not set,
it's unspecified.
You wanna return a value
that says I couldn't do this,
that kinda stuff.
So, Swift introduces a
lot of syntactic sugar,
basically special syntax, to
be able to make it really easy
to use Optional, so much
so that you're gonna think
that Optionals are just some
kind of magic type in Swift.
But underlying it all,
it's just this enum.
There's really nothing
more to it than that.
So let's take a look at
all this syntactic sugar.
First one is how do we declare or to say
that we want this type?
So right here in yellow,
you see that String?.
That is declaring that
hello, this var hello,
is of type Optional,
an Optional whose associated
value is a String.
We would call this an Optional String.
When students are first exposed to this,
they think that the type
of hello is a String
that somehow is modified to be Optional.
No, the type of hello here is an Optional.
Its associated value is a
String, but it's an Optional.
So that's how we declare it.
That is how we type the type,
how we type in with our fingers
the type Optional String.
Now how about setting the value?
Well remember, an Optional
String, it's an Optional.
It only has two cases, none and some.
So we set the none case
by just saying equals nil.
So the keyword nil in
Swift means Optional.none.
That means the not set
case of an Optional is nil.
And similarly, we can say, hello,
this Optional String
equals the String hello.
And Swift is smart enough
to know that that means
set this Optional to the some case
and use hello as the associated value.
So that String, hello
in this case, is set,
and its associated value is hello.
Note that Optionals always start
with an implicit equals nil.
This is nice because remember
that in structs and classes,
all vars have to have an initial value.
We've jumped through a lot of hoops
to try and get all of our vars
to have initial values so far.
Well, Optional, no hoops to jump through
because it gets an implicit equals nil,
or in the enum world,
dot-none, for all vars.
It makes sense, right, because
you've got an Optional here.
It's either set or not set.
Well, it's gonna start out not set.
You could initialize it to
equals hello if you wanted to,
but you can just leave it uninitialized,
but it's not really uninitialized.
It does get initialized to the none case.
So how about accessing the values?
So let's say I have a var like hello,
and it's an Optional,
Optional String let's say,
and I want the String.
How do I get the String?
How do I get that associated value?
Am I gonna have to do, like
you see down here in the right,
switch on it and then do case this?
Of course not.
There's a simple way to
do that switch on it.
Two ways, actually.
One is exclamation point.
If you put an exclamation
point after a var
that is an Optional, it will assume
that it's in the some case, the set case,
and get to you the associated value.
But if you're not, it
crashes your program.
Exclamation point is
truly, well we call it
force unwrapping, because
you're forcing that thing
to be unwrapped and give me that String.
But if that String's not there
because the Optional's
in the not set case,
then it crashes your program.
And we're gonna see in the demo,
this sounds like, ah,
I would never use this.
I would never want my program to crash.
But it can actually be quite useful
in cases where you know
this is never supposed
to be the case.
You can easily find bugs
in development and all that
by making the thing crash and say,
"Wah, that should never have crashed."
But there is a safe way to do it,
and that's by assigning
it to another variable,
a safe variable.
And you do that with if let.
So you see in the lower left corner here,
all the yellow is surrounding
how you do the if let.
You say, if let, some safe version,
equals the Optional, hello is an Optional,
then that safehello is
going to be of type String.
It's going to get the
value if the Optional
is in the some case.
And then inside the
curly braces after there,
if let safehello equals open curly brace,
in that curly brace,
safehello will exist in there,
and it will be a String.
Not an Optional.
It's grabbed the associated
value out of the Optional safely
and is executing.
Now, if that hello were
in the not set case,
then it just wouldn't
even execute that code
that says print(safehello).
Wouldn't even be executed.
It would do the do
something else down there.
That's like, on the right
there, the lower right,
switching on hello.
And in the case that
it's in the not set case,
you're gonna do that
something else that's an else.
Otherwise, if it's in the some case,
then you're just going to
get the String outta there
and do the print(safehello) in there.
So that's how we get the
value, the syntactic sugar
for getting the value of an Optional.
Either forcibly grabbing it out of there
and crashing if we can't find it,
or doing if let to a safe variable,
a safe landing spot for it.
Another cool little syntactic sugar
is the Optional defaulting.
So, this allows you to really
simply provide a default
when you're accessing an Optional
in case that Optional
is in the not set case,
and so it's equal to nil.
Here I have a little constant called x
which is of type Optional
String, Optional String.
And I may have set it to something.
Maybe I set it to nil, maybe
I set it to have something.
But now I'm saying let y equal x.
But if x is nil, use foo.
That's what that question
mark-question mark
means right there.
So, y is always going to be,
in this case, of type String.
Because if x, which is an
Optional, is in the set case
and it has an associated
value, y is gonna get it.
But if x is in the not set case,
then this question mark-question
mark's gonna make y
get the value of foo.
All right, so that's shown on the right
what it would look like
in enum form there.
All right, so Optionals are
best learned about in action,
so we're going to do two major things
with Optionals in this demo.
One, we're gonna fix that
firstIndex of matching
as I mentioned.
And number two, we're gonna make our game,
actually play the Memorize
game, start matching cards.
And to do that, a central piece of that,
is to have a variable that keeps track
of this card that's face-up.
'Cause when there's a card face-up,
I have to match it when
someone picks another card.
So, let's dive right into that demo.
All righty, now that we
know what Optionals are,
we can use it to fix this bogus thing
that we had right here.
What was bogus about this?
Well, we have this function
that found the first index
matching some element in
an Array of Identifiables.
Which it did.
It went through and found the first one.
But if it couldn't find
it, it returned zero.
And zero means the index of
the first thing in the Array,
which is especially bogus
if this Array is empty,
which it could be.
So how're we going to fix this?
We're gonna fix it by
having our return type,
instead of being an Int,
it's going to be an Optional.
Notice I said that this
expression is an Optional.
It's an Optional whose
associated value is an Int,
but it's an Optional.
People sometimes get a little
confused in the beginning
thinking that this is somehow an Int
with some modifier on it.
No, this is a different type from Int.
It's a type called Optional.
This Optional Int, we might call it,
allows us to return nil right here,
or not set value of the Optional,
when we couldn't find it.
And it's really good at
communicating to anyone
who calls this, "I couldn't find this."
Our normal return is returning an Int,
and Swift is smart enough, of course,
that if you have an Optional
Int and you return an Int,
it will return the
Optional in the set state
with the associated value being that Int,
exactly what you want.
So this is it.
Now, this is no longer, in
any way, a bogus function,
it's a completely good function.
And we can use it in the two
places where we call this.
Let's go over here to Grid.
Let's start with this one.
So here is Grid using firstIndex.
It's getting the index.
This local variable right here,
if we option click on it now,
is now of type Optional Int.
Well, that's gonna be a problem down here,
and we'll see an error appear here,
which is "Value of Optional
type Int must be unwrapped
"to a value of Int."
And indeed, layout.location ofItemAt
does not take an Optional as its argument.
It takes an Int.
Now we could take this thing's advice
and say all right, let's unwrap it.
This is how we unwrap an Optional.
This takes an Optional
that's in the set state,
and gets its associated value.
However, when the Optional
is in the not set state,
this crashes your program.
Now some of you might say,
"Whoa, why are we ever
gonna use exclamation point?
"It's terrible, it crashes
my program sometimes."
Well yes, but in this case,
might actually be good
to leave this exclamation point in here.
Because it should never be the case
that we look up the first
index of one of our items,
which we only got by ForEach-ing
through our Item Array.
This should never be nil.
And if it ever were nil,
something is going terribly wrong
somewhere in my code, and
I'd kinda like it to crash
so I find that problem.
But maybe I'm really conservative,
and when I ship my code to my customers,
I really wanna make sure, no matter what,
it doesn't crash with one
of these exclamation points.
So, I could kind of protect my customers
by protecting this code, and say if index
does not equal nil, then do this.
And that will protect this code
so that it can't crash.
Because if index is not nil,
then unwrapping it right here
is always going to work.
But this doesn't build.
And why does this code not build?
It says here "Missing return in a function
"expected to return 'some View'."
Indeed, this function is
supposed to return "some View."
And it does return "some
View" in the case the index
is not nil, but if index is nil,
currently, it returns nothing.
That's a problem.
I'm not even sure what
we would wanna return
in that case here.
So, we're gonna have to take
a little different strategy
to return "some View" here
that has a conditional.
And we've seen it before.
It's over here in our View, ZStack.
ZStack had a conditional.
If the card was face-up, it did one thing.
If it was face-down, it did another thing.
This function right here
that ZStack takes, remember,
is called the ViewBiulder.
It's the same thing that
our GeometryReader takes,
same thing ForEach takes, HStack,
they all take this thing,
ViewBuilder, which is a function,
but it's a special kind of function
where you can put these if-thens in there,
and you can just list Views.
And it turns that all into something
that is "some View."
So the ZStack can have
"some View" as its content.
Well, we can do this same
thing over here in our Grid,
but we don't need to do any layout.
We're doing the layout with
our frame and position.
So we want something
that takes a ViewBuilder
that kinda does nothing.
And there is such a thing.
It's called Group.
So, Group is like a ZStack
or any of these other things
in that its function argument
here is a View builder.
However, it doesn't do anything
to what's inside of here.
It allows you to do the
if and thens and all that,
and you can still list the things,
but it does not lay them out
or try to position them in any way.
And so, our positioning will
continue to work in here.
So, we turn this to a two-line function
instead of a one liner, so
we have to put return in here
to make sure we're returning the Group.
But now we are returning
Group, which is some View.
And Group is just using
the View builder stuff
to go like this.
Now, you might ask, "What does
Group do if index is nil?"
Well, it's gonna return a group
that has some sort of empty content.
Its body is gonna be an empty View.
There's actually a View called EmptyView.
Probably returns that,
but we really don't care.
We're just using the
ViewBuilder functionality here
when we know we can do ifs.
And we're gonna find that Group is useful
in a lot of other situations as well.
As its name implies, it's
good for grouping things.
That's because Group, its View here
is a ViewBuilder View.
That's why we're able to do the if,
but it's also why we would
be able to list some Views,
and thus group them.
So that's really probably the
primary reason Group exists.
That's why it's called Group.
But to be honest, I really
probably wouldn't have
gone through all the
trouble of doing this.
I don't think there's really any reason
to check if this index is nil.
It should never be nil,
as I mentioned before.
So I likely would have
just removed all this.
Gone back to where we were before.
And let this index force unwrap happen.
And if it crashed my
app, it crashed my app.
It never should, and so I
wanna find in development,
and this code is a lot
cleaner without all that
ViewBuilder stuff in there as well.
The other thing I might do is
move this exclamation point
from down here where I'm passing this var
to up here where I'm actually
getting the value of this var.
So, get that firstIndex,
and immediately force unwrap it.
That turns this index variable right here
into an Int, and we can pass it directly.
All right, so there was one other place
where we used firstIndex.
That's in our Model, so let's go over here
and take a look at the damage we wrought
by switching over to firstIndex here.
Here we're gonna use a
little different strategy
to get around the error that
the Optional must be unwrapped
is I'm gonna use the
if in front of my let,
which is a really cool feature.
Just put the if in front,
and then you put curly braces
and do anything you want.
And this anything you want
will only actually happen
if this thing returns non nil.
If it returns nil, this code
just doesn't even get executed.
In here, notice that this
if let allowed us to keep
colon Int as the type of chosenIndex.
We don't need that, by the way,
'cause it's gonna infer it,
but chosenIndex is in fact an Int.
It's only going to actually
exist if this firstIndex
returns a non nil, and
that's the only time
this code's gonna be executed either.
But this does exactly what we want.
It protects us against chosenIndex.
It means choose does nothing.
If we can't find this Card in our cards,
then this does nothing.
That's exactly what we want.
We want it to do nothing.
Let's run and make sure
this Optional business
didn't break anything.
Here we go.
Yup, we can still flip our cards over.
face-up, face-down.
But now, it's time to
try and play the game.
We'll need Optional for that as well.
We're gonna try and make
it so that these cards
will actually match,
and maybe matched cards
will disappear from the game.
That would be cool too.
So how do we do that?
How're we going to play
our game, make it play?
Well, we need a little bit of design.
We are software designers.
We have to think conceptually
how are we gonna make this happen.
So I'm gonna run through,
in my mind, the scenarios.
First, all of my Cards are face-down.
And I click on a Card.
And no matching happens then.
The Card just flips face-up,
which is what it's doing
in our code right there now.
So, okay that's fine.
Second state is I got that one Card up
and I click on a second Card.
Well, that's when I really need to match.
So if there's one Card face-up
and there's a Card clicked on,
that's when I'm gonna play my game.
If there's two Cards face-up
now and I press a third Card,
now I need to essentially turn
those other two Cards face-down.
Whether they're matched or not,
they need to be turned face-down.
And the Card I just touched on,
that's going to be the one that's face-up.
In those three scenarios.
That's all the scenarios there are.
In those three scenarios, the
only time I actually played
a matching game is if there's
one and only one Card face-up
at the time I touch on a new Card.
So I need to detect that case
when there's one and only one.
So I'm gonna have a var
which keeps track of the index
of the one and only face-up Card.
And this is an index into my Array,
so it's gonna be an Int.
But it might be the start of my game
and there's no face-up Card,
or maybe there's two face-up Cards.
So this really needs to be an Optional.
Notice that I didn't
get the error down here
that I haven't initialized this.
There's no errors, but I
haven't initialized this yet.
No errors.
And that's because all Optionals
get initialized to nil automatically.
So there's an equals nil.
You could type it if you want.
But if you don't put it in
there, it's gonna be there.
And that makes sense, right?
Optionals equals nil means it's not set.
Makes total sense that this var
starts out the game not set.
So let's keep going here.
I got this chosenIndex,
and I really only want
to pay attention to Cards that
are obviously in my Array,
but also that are not already face-up.
If a Card is already
face-up and I tap on it,
I'm just gonna ignore it.
Now, you'd think this would work, right?
Get the chosenIndex here,
and the chosenIndex is not face-up.
But it's complaining that
chosenIndex is unresolved.
So if you wanna do an and like this
where you're saying if let of something
and then you wanna do
and on that something,
instead of and here,
you're gonna use comma.
So comma is like a sequential and,
where it does this first.
Then, that's done, it can do
this, and chosenIndex is set.
And you can even have more of these,
like I might also want to ignore Cards
where this shows an
index is not not matched.
So I'm only gonna touch on Cards
that are face-up and unmatched.
Otherwise I just ignore those Cards.
We use that comma notation
quite a bit with these if lets.
Inside here, I know
that I've chosen a Card
that was face-down and not yet matched.
So I just wanna see if
there's one and only one
face-up Card right now, so I'm gonna say
if I can let potentialMatchIndex
equal the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard,
now I might have a match
because there's one and
only one face-up Card.
I just turned another Card over.
We need to try and match it.
No problem, if the Cards
at the chosenIndex,
if its contents, remember the content
on the Card right here,
that's what's on the Card,
equals the Cards at the
potentialMatchIndex content,
then woohoo, got a match.
Now this is making an error happen.
Why is this making an error?
It says "Binary operator
equals-equals cannot be applied
"to two CardContent operands."
Hmm, indeed both of these
things are type CardContent.
That's our don't-care down here.
Why can't we do
equals-equals on CardContent?
It's a String, right, emoji String.
Op, wait a second.
This is a generic memory
game playing thing.
These are no emoji in there.
They're CardContent, which
is a don't-care for us.
This could be anything, Images,
Strings, Ints, whatever.
We're trying to say equals-equals.
If it's a String, okay, it works fine.
What if it's an Image?
Can you say one Image
equals-equals another?
Maybe not, I don't know.
Equals-equals is not something
that just applies to everything.
And in fact, how does
equals-equals work in Swift?
Equals-equals in Swift, believe
it or not, is not built in
to the language.
It uses a feature in
Swift called operators
that lets you associate
an operator like this
with a function.
And that's exactly what equal-equals does.
It associates it with the
type function equals-equals.
Now, equals-equals might
seem like a funny name
for a function in Swift.
And it is kinda funny, but also remember
that smiley face, the emoji smiley face,
is a valid function name in Swift.
Any Unicode characters,
pretty much, is valid Swift.
So, equals-equals is just
as valid as smiley face.
So this equal-equals
function is a type function,
and it just takes two arguments,
which is the two things on
either side of the equals,
and it returns a bool, whether
they're the same or not.
That's it, that's exactly
what you'd expect.
But not every type has
this equals-equals in it.
Only some types that can actually
check for equality have that.
But luckily, that equals-equals function
is in a protocol called Equatable,
so we can use our
constrains and gains here
to say where our CardContent
implements Equatable.
In other words, we're only gonna work,
our MemoryGame only works
when our CardContent
can be equaled-equaled,
could be Equatable.
Let's go look at this
protocol in the documentation.
So I'm gonna do Option, click.
This is a kind of top-level
documentation about it,
but let's go into the doc.
Equal-equal's a very important protocol.
You can see it's got a lot of explanation
of what it means to say
something is equal-equal
to something else, transitive
property, all this business.
But when you get down to the
list of functions about it,
there's only one that is required.
You see this required?
That means it is part of the protocol,
and there's no default implementation
by an extension anywhere,
so you must implement this.
And it's exactly what I said,
a static, a type function
that takes two of those things,
remember in the slides,
we had is greater than
and you had self, so the
argument is greater than
with an Int or it was a President.
Same thing here.
If you have equals-equals
and if let's a String,
then Self and Self would
be String and String,
so it takes two Strings and compares them.
If it's Int, it takes two Ints, whatever.
This is the only function
you have to implement.
Really easy function, simple
function to understand,
although you have to read
all this to make sure
you really understand it.
And the only one we have
to implement in Equatable.
All these other ones are not required
because you get them
for free by extension.
Swift Foundation gives you these things
for tuples and other
things here automatically.
And does not equals, it
gives you that one for free.
They're all based on
the equals-equals here.
This is a protocol, protocol Equatable.
So we are just forcing, or constraining,
our CardContent, our
don't-care, to be Equatable.
We care a little bit.
We care that it's Equatable
so we can compare it.
All right, so if these two things match,
then I'm just gonna say they're matched.
cards at the chosenIndex,
isMatched equals true.
And of course the cards at
the potentialMatchIndex,
it did turn out to be a match,
so its isMatched also equals true.
So these Cards are matched.
That's awesome.
Notice that no matter what,
whether they match or not,
there are two Cards face-up now.
So the index of the one and
only face-up Card is nil.
There's not one and only one face-up Card.
There are two, so that means this is nil.
What about the else case here?
So in this case, there is not
one and only one face-up Card.
So there's either zero
or there's more than one.
In this case, we wanna turn
all the Cards face-down
except for the one we
just chose of course.
So we're gonna do a little for loop,
index in our cards.indices
And we're just gonna go
for every single Card
isFaceUp equals false, and we'll make sure
that we turn our Card to
true, turn it face-up.
Also notice in this case
that the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
is our chosenIndex.
'Cause I just turned
all of these face-down
and I'm gonna turn this one back up,
and so it's going to be
the only face-up Card.
So that's it.
This is our logic.
We don't need this Card chosen
to print anymore right there.
And that's the entirety
of making this work.
So let's run, see if our
game plays like we want.
Well, this game turns out
to be one of the easiest
memory games out there because
all the Cards start face-up.
So, that's no good.
Let's go back to our Model here
and change it so that all
the Cards start face-down.
I think that's gonna make for
a much more challenging game.
All right, let's try it.
Ghost, yeah.
Pumpkin, oh no, no match.
Ghost, yeah, spider, no, no, not again.
Pumpkin, ah, I think I
know where the pumpkin is.
It's right here.
Yes.
And then how about spider?
Oh, now notice that it did turn
my matched cards face-down,
and if I try to touch on them,
I'm currently clicking
on these repeatedly,
they don't turn back up because
they're already matched.
And we ignore cards that
are already matched.
But this is not very good UI
to have these face-down cards
that you can't touch on, it does nothing.
I really wanna take these away.
So if they're matched,
I'm gonna take them away.
So let's go back to our UI and do that.
Here's our CardView.
And here's where the cards
are face-up, no problem there.
Here's where they're face-down.
I'm gonna say if the Card is not matched,
then I'll draw it.
But if it is matched and it's face-down,
I'm gonna draw nothing.
Again, this is ViewBuilder.
It's got these simple ifs.
You can even nest these
ifs inside the elses
or inside the ifs of other ifs.
Nested ifs are okay.
And notice we don't
even need an else here.
ViewBuilder knows how
to deal with the fact
that the if didn't happen, and
so nothing is gonna be here.
Essentially there's an empty View.
And in fact in SwiftUI, there
is a View called EmptyView.
So that's what this
ViewBuilder is going to make
for ZStack in the case
the Cards are face-down.
See if that fixes that.
And we get pumpkin, spider, ghost.
Oh, got a match, ready?
Woo, it took them away.
Another match, takes those away.
Okay, this is excellent.
Our game is basically
functioning beautifully.
So one last thing I wanna
do, though, to my Model.
I'm a little concerned
that I have this state,
the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard,
that I'm having to keep in sync
with my changes to the Cards.
And this is kind of an
error-prone way to program
when you have state in two places.
The indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
is here,
and it's also determinable
from these Cards.
So, let's use a computed var here instead
and get from the Cards the
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard.
And we're also going to do here a set
so that if someone sets the
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard,
we turn all the other Cards face-down.
This is the first time you've
seen a computed property
that we can get the value of,
but we can also set the value of.
Let's do the set one first.
It's kind of the simpler of the two.
How are we going to react when someone
sets the value of the
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard?
Well in that case, we need to go through
all of our Cards.
I'm just gonna go
through our indices here.
And I'm gonna pretty much set
all the Cards to be face-down.
Except I don't wanna do that
if this is the one that you said
was the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard.
Inside this set, there's a
special variable called newValue.
So I can tell you if
index equals newValue,
the value that the person
said this was equal to,
then it's face-up.
So newValue is the special var,
only appears inside this
set for a computed property.
And it's whatever the people set this to.
Could be nil, by the way.
This newValue, it's an
Optional, so it could be nil.
Index is an Int, and Int is never equal to
an Optional that's not set,
so this equals would only be true
if this is an Optional that's set
and its associated integer
matches this integer
So that's it for set, pretty simple.
What about getting?
Well, to get it, I really
need to look at all the Cards
and see which ones are face-up
and see if there's only one.
So let's start by getting
all the face-up Cards.
So I'm gonna say faceUpCardIndices.
It's gonna be an Array of Int.
By the way, I'm gonna use
this syntax right here
to mean Array of Int.
This is exactly the same as Array of Int.
I'm gonna say that out in the real world,
this is actually slightly
preferred as the syntax.
Not 100% sure of that,
but it sure seems to me
people prefer this over Array of Int.
I like Array of Int.
It's clearer that that's a generic,
and the don't-care is Int and all that,
but Arrays are extremely common to use,
so I can understand the shorthand there.
So now, how am I gonna get
this faceUpCardIndices?
It's starting empty right there,
so I'm gonna go for
index in cards.indices,
go through all my Cards.
If a Card at a certain index is face-up,
then I'm gonna put it in
the faceUpCardIndices,
append that index.
All right, now I have all
the face-up Card indices.
I'm gonna say if the
faceUpCardIndices.count equals one,
so one and only one Card,
then I'm gonna return that
faceUpCardIndices sub zero.
By the way, there's another
nice little var for that,
which is .first.
And when we're typing first,
notice that its return type of this var,
or the type of this var,
is Int, question mark,
Optional Int, why?
Because the Array might be empty.
So if you say your Array.first,
and the Array is empty,
this will return nil.
There's Swift using Optionals
to communicate something.
Otherwise, I'm gonna return nil.
Because if there's not exactly one Card
in the face-up Card list, then obviously,
the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
is nil, and that's it.
So now that this is calculated,
I don't have to work so hard
to make sure it's kept in sync.
For example, in here, I
don't even need to say
that the
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard is nil.
Just get rid of that code altogether
because it's always going to know
when there's two face-up Cards.
It calculates it.
Kinda similarly down here, because I set
the one and only face-up
Card to be this index,
I don't need to set all
the rest of them face-down.
That's gonna be automatically
done by the setter of this.
And also, this true of turning it face-up,
we only need to do in here because again,
setting the indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
is going to make sure that
this chosenIndex is face-up.
So that makes this code
really pretty minimal
to play an entire card-matching game.
Now that's at the expense
of a lot of code up here.
And we're gonna fix that in a second,
but let's make sure that
this has not broken anything.
Here we go.
Pumpkin, spider, spider,
spider, pumpkin, all right.
Ghost, no, pumpkin, ghost,
ghost, ghost, pumpkin.
So this is working.
Beautiful looking code right here.
Little bit more code here than we need.
So how can we reduce this code a bit?
Down here, I can only think of one thing
to make this a little more efficient,
which is that here I'm
saying if something is true,
then set this to true, else set it false.
I could just take this and put it here.
Then I don't need all
the rest of this overhead
of the syntax of all this if.
So I'm just gonna set every Card.
I'm gonna set it to false unless the index
is equal to what the person
said this was equal to,
like I'm doing right here.
So that's nice.
That's pretty minimal code.
What about all this?
Believe it or not, I'm gonna make it
so this is one line of code.
You know we love one line
of code in this class.
Your first homework
assignment proved that.
So how am I gonna make
this one line of code?
I'm gonna start by having
all of this right here
be one line, and I'm gonna do that
with a function in a range called filter.
So I'm gonna take my cards
indices, that's a range
between zero, dot dot,
less than cards.count.
And call this function filter.
You see filter here in range.
It returns an Array of Int.
You see on the left here, Array of Int.
And those Ints are all
the Ints in this range
where this function that takes an Int
and returns a bool returns true.
So it looks like this.
Let's double-click on this.
Here it is.
I can double-click on this even.
It fills it in for me.
This is a function, an in-line function,
that takes an Int and returns a Bool.
And we're supposed to return
whether to include this Int,
which is one of the indices,
in the resulting faceUpCardIndices.
We're making a new Array by
filtering out these other ones.
This is what the index is,
so we'll call this index.
And what do we wanna do?
We wanna say return Cards at that index,
dot, isFaceUp.
So this is all we wanna do.
Of course, we like to make
things less code in Swift,
so we can take away this return.
Maybe we'll put this up here, like this.
We can infer this return type.
Don't need that, don't need
these parentheses in there.
There's another thing I
didn't show you last time
that we can do to make these even smaller,
which is that the arguments
are specified here
with index in.
You can get rid of that
and just use dollar-zero,
and dollar-one, and dollar-two
for each of the arguments.
Dollar-zero for the first argument,
dollar-one for the second
argument, et cetera.
So we're almost there.
This is all gone right here.
And because we now just
calculate this in one fell swoop,
we're getting this warning here
that this can now be a let, which it can.
How about this?
How do we get rid of this?
What's going on here?
Here we're actually just
saying to the Array of indices,
if there's only one of you, give it to me.
Otherwise, give me nil.
Well, why don't we extend Array,
using extension to Array, to
have a var that does this?
'Cause that seems like a
reasonable Array thing.
Hey Mr. Array, give me the
only thing in yourself,
otherwise give me nil.
So let's create another little
extension for Array here.
Do a Swift file.
We'll call this one Array+Only
since it returns the
only thing in an Array.
And this extension to Array
is gonna extend all Arrays.
This extension to Array
is not like this one
where it's where Element's Identifiable.
This one extends to all Arrays.
It's gonna add this var
I'm gonna call only.
It's of type Element, question
mark, Optional Element.
And it's computed, and it
just returns the Array's count
equals one, first, colon, nil.
So this is in Array, so count
is the count of the Array.
And if that equals one,
we're using this ternary operator here
to return the first item in the Array.
Otherwise nil.
Super simple, and that super simple code
makes this all go away right here.
We don't need any of this.
Instead, we can just
say dot-only over here,
and get rid of all of this.
Just return this.
But since this is now a
one-liner, we don't need return.
And we can even make
it all be one line here
like this as well.
And this code has all of a
sudden gotten a lot more compact.
So let's make sure we
didn't break anything there.
Click, yeah, ooh, what, yay, it works.
Now this has set up this
beautifully for your homework.
You're going to now take this working game
and do some enhancements to it.
So check out the writeup for that.
And we'll see you next lecture.
- [Narrator] For more, please
visit us at stanford.edu.